<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</title>
    <link>http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.AI</link>
    <description>cs.AI updates on the arXiv.org e-print archive.</description>
    <atom:link href="http://rss.arxiv.org/rss/cs.AI" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 04:00:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <managingEditor>rss-help@arxiv.org</managingEditor>
    <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <skipDays>
      <day>Sunday</day>
      <day>Saturday</day>
    </skipDays>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Preferences in AI Alignment</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.16984</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.16984v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The dominant practice of AI alignment assumes (1) that preferences are an adequate representation of human values, (2) that human rationality can be understood in terms of maximizing the satisfaction of preferences, and (3) that AI systems should be aligned with the preferences of one or more humans to ensure that they behave safely and in accordance with our values. Whether implicitly followed or explicitly endorsed, these commitments constitute what we term a preferentist approach to AI alignment. In this paper, we characterize and challenge the preferentist approach, describing conceptual and technical alternatives that are ripe for further research. We first survey the limits of rational choice theory as a descriptive model, explaining how preferences fail to capture the thick semantic content of human values, and how utility representations neglect the possible incommensurability of those values. We then critique the normativity of expected utility theory (EUT) for humans and AI, drawing upon arguments showing how rational agents need not comply with EUT, while highlighting how EUT is silent on which preferences are normatively acceptable. Finally, we argue that these limitations motivate a reframing of the targets of AI alignment: Instead of alignment with the preferences of a human user, developer, or humanity-writ-large, AI systems should be aligned with normative standards appropriate to their social roles, such as the role of a general-purpose assistant. Furthermore, these standards should be negotiated and agreed upon by all relevant stakeholders. On this alternative conception of alignment, a multiplicity of AI systems will be able to serve diverse ends, aligned with normative standards that promote mutual benefit and limit harm despite our plural and divergent values.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.16984v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tan Zhi-Xuan, Micah Carroll, Matija Franklin, Hal Ashton</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strategic Arms with Side Communication Prevail Over Low-Regret MAB Algorithms</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.17101</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.17101v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In the strategic multi-armed bandit setting, when arms possess perfect information about the player's behavior, they can establish an equilibrium where: 1. they retain almost all of their value, 2. they leave the player with a substantial (linear) regret. This study illustrates that, even if complete information is not publicly available to all arms but is shared among them, it is possible to achieve a similar equilibrium. The primary challenge lies in designing a communication protocol that incentivizes the arms to communicate truthfully.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.17101v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1109/ICASSP48485.2024.10446895</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>ICASSP 2024 - 2024 IEEE International Conference on Acoustics, Speech and Signal Processing (ICASSP), 2024, pp.7435-7439</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Ahmed Ben Yahmed (CREST, ENSAE Paris), Cl\'ement Calauz\`enes (CREST, ENSAE Paris), Vianney Perchet (CREST, ENSAE Paris)</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Identifying and Clustering Counter Relationships of Team Compositions in PvP Games for Efficient Balance Analysis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.17180</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.17180v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: How can balance be quantified in game settings? This question is crucial for game designers, especially in player-versus-player (PvP) games, where analyzing the strength relations among predefined team compositions-such as hero combinations in multiplayer online battle arena (MOBA) games or decks in card games-is essential for enhancing gameplay and achieving balance. We have developed two advanced measures that extend beyond the simplistic win rate to quantify balance in zero-sum competitive scenarios. These measures are derived from win value estimations, which employ strength rating approximations via the Bradley-Terry model and counter relationship approximations via vector quantization, significantly reducing the computational complexity associated with traditional win value estimations. Throughout the learning process of these models, we identify useful categories of compositions and pinpoint their counter relationships, aligning with the experiences of human players without requiring specific game knowledge. Our methodology hinges on a simple technique to enhance codebook utilization in discrete representation with a deterministic vector quantization process for an extremely small state space. Our framework has been validated in popular online games, including Age of Empires II, Hearthstone, Brawl Stars, and League of Legends. The accuracy of the observed strength relations in these games is comparable to traditional pairwise win value predictions, while also offering a more manageable complexity for analysis. Ultimately, our findings contribute to a deeper understanding of PvP game dynamics and present a methodology that significantly improves game balance evaluation and design.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.17180v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.GT</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.MA</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chiu-Chou Lin, Yu-Wei Shih, Kuei-Ting Kuo, Yu-Cheng Chen, Chien-Hua Chen, Wei-Chen Chiu, I-Chen Wu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reasoning with maximal consistent signatures</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.17190</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.17190v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We analyse a specific instance of the general approach of reasoning based on forgetting by Lang and Marquis. More precisely, we discuss an approach for reasoning with inconsistent information using maximal consistent subsignatures, where a maximal consistent subsignature is a maximal set of propositions such that forgetting the remaining propositions restores consistency. We analyse maximal consistent subsignatures and the corresponding minimal inconsistent subsignatures in-depth and show, among others, that the hitting set duality applies for them as well. We further analyse inference relations based on maximal consistent subsignatures wrt. rationality postulates from non-monotonic reasoning and computational complexity. We also consider the relationship of our approach with inconsistency measurement and paraconsistent reasoning.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.17190v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Matthias Thimm, Jandson Santos Ribeiro Santos</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards Symbolic XAI -- Explanation Through Human Understandable Logical Relationships Between Features</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.17198</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.17198v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Explainable Artificial Intelligence (XAI) plays a crucial role in fostering transparency and trust in AI systems, where traditional XAI approaches typically offer one level of abstraction for explanations, often in the form of heatmaps highlighting single or multiple input features. However, we ask whether abstract reasoning or problem-solving strategies of a model may also be relevant, as these align more closely with how humans approach solutions to problems. We propose a framework, called Symbolic XAI, that attributes relevance to symbolic queries expressing logical relationships between input features, thereby capturing the abstract reasoning behind a model's predictions. The methodology is built upon a simple yet general multi-order decomposition of model predictions. This decomposition can be specified using higher-order propagation-based relevance methods, such as GNN-LRP, or perturbation-based explanation methods commonly used in XAI. The effectiveness of our framework is demonstrated in the domains of natural language processing (NLP), vision, and quantum chemistry (QC), where abstract symbolic domain knowledge is abundant and of significant interest to users. The Symbolic XAI framework provides an understanding of the model's decision-making process that is both flexible for customization by the user and human-readable through logical formulas.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.17198v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Thomas Schnake, Farnoush Rezaei Jafaria, Jonas Lederer, Ping Xiong, Shinichi Nakajima, Stefan Gugler, Gr\'egoire Montavon, Klaus-Robert M\"uller</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A methodological framework for Resilience as a Service (RaaS) in multimodal urban transportation networks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.17233</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.17233v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Public transportation systems are experiencing an increase in commuter traffic. This increase underscores the need for resilience strategies to manage unexpected service disruptions, ensuring rapid and effective responses that minimize adverse effects on stakeholders and enhance the system's ability to maintain essential functions and recover quickly. This study aims to explore the management of public transport disruptions through resilience as a service (RaaS) strategies, developing an optimization model to effectively allocate resources and minimize the cost for operators and passengers. The proposed model includes multiple transportation options, such as buses, taxis, and automated vans, and evaluates them as bridging alternatives to rail-disrupted services based on factors such as their availability, capacity, speed, and proximity to the disrupted station. This ensures that the most suitable vehicles are deployed to maintain service continuity. Applied to a case study in the Ile de France region, Paris and suburbs, complemented by a microscopic simulation, the model is compared to existing solutions such as bus bridging and reserve fleets. The results highlight the model's performance in minimizing costs and enhancing stakeholder satisfaction, optimizing transport management during disruptions.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.17233v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sara Jaber (Univ. Gustave Eiffel, COSYS, GRETTIA, Paris, France,VEDECOM, mobiLAB, Department of new solutions of mobility services,shared energy, Versailles, France), Mostafa Ameli (Univ. Gustave Eiffel, COSYS, GRETTIA, Paris, France), S. M. Hassan Mahdavi (VEDECOM, mobiLAB, Department of new solutions of mobility services,shared energy, Versailles, France), Neila Bhouri (Univ. Gustave Eiffel, COSYS, GRETTIA, Paris, France)</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Flexible and Effective Mixing of Large Language Models into a Mixture of Domain Experts</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.17280</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.17280v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: We present a toolkit for creating low-cost Mixture-of-Domain-Experts (MOE) from trained models. The toolkit can be used for creating a mixture from models or from adapters. We perform extensive tests and offer guidance on defining the architecture of the resulting MOE using the toolkit. A public repository is available.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.17280v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Rhui Dih Lee, Laura Wynter, Raghu Kiran Ganti</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bridging Domain Knowledge and Process Discovery Using Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.17316</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.17316v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Discovering good process models is essential for different process analysis tasks such as conformance checking and process improvements. Automated process discovery methods often overlook valuable domain knowledge. This knowledge, including insights from domain experts and detailed process documentation, remains largely untapped during process discovery. This paper leverages Large Language Models (LLMs) to integrate such knowledge directly into process discovery. We use rules derived from LLMs to guide model construction, ensuring alignment with both domain knowledge and actual process executions. By integrating LLMs, we create a bridge between process knowledge expressed in natural language and the discovery of robust process models, advancing process discovery methodologies significantly. To showcase the usability of our framework, we conducted a case study with the UWV employee insurance agency, demonstrating its practical benefits and effectiveness.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.17316v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ali Norouzifar, Humam Kourani, Marcus Dees, Wil van der Aalst</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Traffic expertise meets residual RL: Knowledge-informed model-based residual reinforcement learning for CAV trajectory control</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.17380</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.17380v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Model-based reinforcement learning (RL) is anticipated to exhibit higher sample efficiency compared to model-free RL by utilizing a virtual environment model. However, it is challenging to obtain sufficiently accurate representations of the environmental dynamics due to uncertainties in complex systems and environments. An inaccurate environment model may degrade the sample efficiency and performance of model-based RL. Furthermore, while model-based RL can improve sample efficiency, it often still requires substantial training time to learn from scratch, potentially limiting its advantages over model-free approaches. To address these challenges, this paper introduces a knowledge-informed model-based residual reinforcement learning framework aimed at enhancing learning efficiency by infusing established expert knowledge into the learning process and avoiding the issue of beginning from zero. Our approach integrates traffic expert knowledge into a virtual environment model, employing the Intelligent Driver Model (IDM) for basic dynamics and neural networks for residual dynamics, thus ensuring adaptability to complex scenarios. We propose a novel strategy that combines traditional control methods with residual RL, facilitating efficient learning and policy optimization without the need to learn from scratch. The proposed approach is applied to CAV trajectory control tasks for the dissipation of stop-and-go waves in mixed traffic flow. Experimental results demonstrate that our proposed approach enables the CAV agent to achieve superior performance in trajectory control compared to the baseline agents in terms of sample efficiency, traffic flow smoothness and traffic mobility. The source code and supplementary materials are available at https://github.com/zihaosheng/traffic-expertise-RL/.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.17380v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zihao Sheng, Zilin Huang, Sikai Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Effect of Explanation Content and Format on User Comprehension and Trust</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.17401</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.17401v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: In recent years, various methods have been introduced for explaining the outputs of "black-box" AI models. However, it is not well understood whether users actually comprehend and trust these explanations. In this paper, we focus on explanations for a regression tool for assessing cancer risk and examine the effect of the explanations' content and format on the user-centric metrics of comprehension and trust. Regarding content, we experiment with two explanation methods: the popular SHAP, based on game-theoretic notions and thus potentially complex for everyday users to comprehend, and occlusion-1, based on feature occlusion which may be more comprehensible. Regarding format, we present SHAP explanations as charts (SC), as is conventional, and occlusion-1 explanations as charts (OC) as well as text (OT), to which their simpler nature also lends itself. The experiments amount to user studies questioning participants, with two different levels of expertise (the general population and those with some medical training), on their subjective and objective comprehension of and trust in explanations for the outputs of the regression tool. In both studies we found a clear preference in terms of subjective comprehension and trust for occlusion-1 over SHAP explanations in general, when comparing based on content. However, direct comparisons of explanations when controlling for format only revealed evidence for OT over SC explanations in most cases, suggesting that the dominance of occlusion-1 over SHAP explanations may be driven by a preference for text over charts as explanations. Finally, we found no evidence of a difference between the explanation types in terms of objective comprehension. Thus overall, the choice of the content and format of explanations needs careful attention, since in some contexts format, rather than content, may play the critical role in improving user experience.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.17401v1</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>new</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Antonio Rago, Bence Palfi, Purin Sukpanichnant, Hannibal Nabli, Kavyesh Vivek, Olga Kostopoulou, James Kinross, Francesca Toni</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Effective Information Theoretic Framework for Channel Pruning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.16772</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.16772v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Channel pruning is a promising method for accelerating and compressing convolutional neural networks. However, current pruning algorithms still remain unsolved problems that how to assign layer-wise pruning ratios properly and discard the least important channels with a convincing criterion. In this paper, we present a novel channel pruning approach via information theory and interpretability of neural networks. Specifically, we regard information entropy as the expected amount of information for convolutional layers. In addition, if we suppose a matrix as a system of linear equations, a higher-rank matrix represents there exist more solutions to it, which indicates more uncertainty. From the point of view of information theory, the rank can also describe the amount of information. In a neural network, considering the rank and entropy as two information indicators of convolutional layers, we propose a fusion function to reach a compromise of them, where the fusion results are defined as ``information concentration''. When pre-defining layer-wise pruning ratios, we employ the information concentration as a reference instead of heuristic and engineering tuning to provide a more interpretable solution. Moreover, we leverage Shapley values, which are a potent tool in the interpretability of neural networks, to evaluate the channel contributions and discard the least important channels for model compression while maintaining its performance. Extensive experiments demonstrate the effectiveness and promising performance of our method. For example, our method improves the accuracy by 0.21% when reducing 45.5% FLOPs and removing 40.3% parameters for ResNet-56 on CIFAR-10. Moreover, our method obtains loss in Top-1/Top-5 accuracies of 0.43%/0.11% by reducing 41.6% FLOPs and removing 35.0% parameters for ResNet-50 on ImageNet.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.16772v1</guid>
      <category>cs.IT</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>math.IT</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1109/TNNLS.2024.3365194</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Yihao Chen, Zefang Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Online Behavior Modification for Expressive User Control of RL-Trained Robots</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.16776</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.16776v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Reinforcement Learning (RL) is an effective method for robots to learn tasks. However, in typical RL, end-users have little to no control over how the robot does the task after the robot has been deployed. To address this, we introduce the idea of online behavior modification, a paradigm in which users have control over behavior features of a robot in real time as it autonomously completes a task using an RL-trained policy. To show the value of this user-centered formulation for human-robot interaction, we present a behavior diversity based algorithm, Adjustable Control Of RL Dynamics (ACORD), and demonstrate its applicability to online behavior modification in simulation and a user study. In the study (n=23) users adjust the style of paintings as a robot traces a shape autonomously. We compare ACORD to RL and Shared Autonomy (SA), and show ACORD affords user-preferred levels of control and expression, comparable to SA, but with the potential for autonomous execution and robustness of RL.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.16776v1</guid>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1145/3610977.3634947</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Isaac Sheidlower, Mavis Murdock, Emma Bethel, Reuben M. Aronson, Elaine Schaertl Short</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inductive Learning of Logical Theories with LLMs: A Complexity-graded Analysis</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.16779</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.16779v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: This work presents a novel systematic methodology to analyse the capabilities and limitations of Large Language Models (LLMs) with feedback from a formal inference engine, on logic theory induction. The analysis is complexity-graded w.r.t. rule dependency structure, allowing quantification of specific inference challenges on LLM performance. Integrating LLMs with formal methods is a promising frontier in the Natural Language Processing field, as an important avenue for improving model inference control and explainability. In particular, inductive learning over complex sets of facts and rules, poses unique challenges for current autoregressive models, as they lack explicit symbolic grounding. While they can be complemented by formal systems, the properties delivered by LLMs regarding inductive learning, are not well understood and quantified. Empirical results indicate that the largest LLMs can achieve competitive results against a SOTA Inductive Logic Programming (ILP) system baseline, but also that tracking long predicate relationship chains is a more difficult obstacle than theory complexity for the LLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.16779v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LO</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jo\~ao Pedro Gandarela, Danilo S. Carvalho, Andr\'e Freitas</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>$EvoAl^{2048}$</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.16780</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.16780v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: As AI solutions enter safety-critical products, the explainability and interpretability of solutions generated by AI products become increasingly important. In the long term, such explanations are the key to gaining users' acceptance of AI-based systems' decisions. We report on applying a model-driven-based optimisation to search for an interpretable and explainable policy that solves the game 2048. This paper describes a solution to the GECCO'24 Interpretable Control Competition using the open-source software EvoAl. We aimed to develop an approach for creating interpretable policies that are easy to adapt to new ideas.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.16780v1</guid>
      <category>cs.NE</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Bernhard J. Berger (University of Rostock, Software Engineering Chair Rostock, Germany, Hamburg University of Technology, Institute of Embedded Systems, Germany), Christina Plump (DFKI - Cyber-Physical Systems Bremen, Germany), Rolf Drechsler (University of Bremen, Departments of Mathematics and Computer Science, DFKI - Cyber-Physical Systems Bremen, Germany)</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uncertainty-aware segmentation for rainfall prediction post processing</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.16792</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.16792v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Accurate precipitation forecasts are crucial for applications such as flood management, agricultural planning, water resource allocation, and weather warnings. Despite advances in numerical weather prediction (NWP) models, they still exhibit significant biases and uncertainties, especially at high spatial and temporal resolutions. To address these limitations, we explore uncertainty-aware deep learning models for post-processing daily cumulative quantitative precipitation forecasts to obtain forecast uncertainties that lead to a better trade-off between accuracy and reliability. Our study compares different state-of-the-art models, and we propose a variant of the well-known SDE-Net, called SDE U-Net, tailored to segmentation problems like ours. We evaluate its performance for both typical and intense precipitation events.
  Our results show that all deep learning models significantly outperform the average baseline NWP solution, with our implementation of the SDE U-Net showing the best trade-off between accuracy and reliability. Integrating these models, which account for uncertainty, into operational forecasting systems can improve decision-making and preparedness for weather-related events.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.16792v1</guid>
      <category>physics.ao-ph</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Simone Monaco, Luca Monaco, Daniele Apiletti</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generative AI in Ship Design</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.16798</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.16798v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: The process of ship design is intricate, heavily influenced by the hull form which accounts for approximately 70% of the total cost. Traditional methods rely on human-driven iterative processes based on naval architecture principles and engineering analysis. In contrast, generative AI presents a novel approach, utilizing computational algorithms rooted in machine learning and artificial intelligence to optimize ship hull design. This report outlines the systematic creation of a generative AI for this purpose, involving steps such as dataset collection, model architecture selection, training, and validation. Utilizing the "SHIP-D" dataset, consisting of 30,000 hull forms, the report adopts the Gaussian Mixture Model (GMM) as the generative model architecture. GMMs offer a statistical framework to analyze data distribution, crucial for generating innovative ship designs efficiently. Overall, this approach holds promise in revolutionizing ship design by exploring a broader design space and integrating multidisciplinary optimization objectives effectively.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.16798v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sahil Thakur, Navneet V Saxena, Prof Sitikantha Roy</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HLogformer: A Hierarchical Transformer for Representing Log Data</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.16803</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.16803v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Transformers have gained widespread acclaim for their versatility in handling diverse data structures, yet their application to log data remains underexplored. Log data, characterized by its hierarchical, dictionary-like structure, poses unique challenges when processed using conventional transformer models. Traditional methods often rely on manually crafted templates for parsing logs, a process that is labor-intensive and lacks generalizability. Additionally, the linear treatment of log sequences by standard transformers neglects the rich, nested relationships within log entries, leading to suboptimal representations and excessive memory usage.
  To address these issues, we introduce HLogformer, a novel hierarchical transformer framework specifically designed for log data. HLogformer leverages the hierarchical structure of log entries to significantly reduce memory costs and enhance representation learning. Unlike traditional models that treat log data as flat sequences, our framework processes log entries in a manner that respects their inherent hierarchical organization. This approach ensures comprehensive encoding of both fine-grained details and broader contextual relationships.
  Our contributions are threefold: First, HLogformer is the first framework to design a dynamic hierarchical transformer tailored for dictionary-like log data. Second, it dramatically reduces memory costs associated with processing extensive log sequences. Third, comprehensive experiments demonstrate that HLogformer more effectively encodes hierarchical contextual information, proving to be highly effective for downstream tasks such as synthetic anomaly detection and product recommendation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.16803v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhichao Hou, Mina Ghashami, Mikhail Kuznetsov, MohamadAli Torkamani</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Physics-Informed Neural Networks and Extensions</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.16806</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.16806v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: In this paper, we review the new method Physics-Informed Neural Networks (PINNs) that has become the main pillar in scientific machine learning, we present recent practical extensions, and provide a specific example in data-driven discovery of governing differential equations.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.16806v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Maziar Raissi, Paris Perdikaris, Nazanin Ahmadi, George Em Karniadakis</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GSTAM: Efficient Graph Distillation with Structural Attention-Matching</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.16871</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.16871v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Graph distillation has emerged as a solution for reducing large graph datasets to smaller, more manageable, and informative ones. Existing methods primarily target node classification, involve computationally intensive processes, and fail to capture the true distribution of the full graph dataset. To address these issues, we introduce Graph Distillation with Structural Attention Matching (GSTAM), a novel method for condensing graph classification datasets. GSTAM leverages the attention maps of GNNs to distill structural information from the original dataset into synthetic graphs. The structural attention-matching mechanism exploits the areas of the input graph that GNNs prioritize for classification, effectively distilling such information into the synthetic graphs and improving overall distillation performance. Comprehensive experiments demonstrate GSTAM's superiority over existing methods, achieving 0.45% to 6.5% better performance in extreme condensation ratios, highlighting its potential use in advancing distillation for graph classification tasks (Code available at https://github.com/arashrasti96/GSTAM).</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.16871v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Arash Rasti-Meymandi, Ahmad Sajedi, Zhaopan Xu, Konstantinos N. Plataniotis</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing Inference Privacy Risks Through Gradients in Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.16913</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.16913v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: In distributed learning settings, models are iteratively updated with shared gradients computed from potentially sensitive user data. While previous work has studied various privacy risks of sharing gradients, our paper aims to provide a systematic approach to analyze private information leakage from gradients. We present a unified game-based framework that encompasses a broad range of attacks including attribute, property, distributional, and user disclosures. We investigate how different uncertainties of the adversary affect their inferential power via extensive experiments on five datasets across various data modalities. Our results demonstrate the inefficacy of solely relying on data aggregation to achieve privacy against inference attacks in distributed learning. We further evaluate five types of defenses, namely, gradient pruning, signed gradient descent, adversarial perturbations, variational information bottleneck, and differential privacy, under both static and adaptive adversary settings. We provide an information-theoretic view for analyzing the effectiveness of these defenses against inference from gradients. Finally, we introduce a method for auditing attribute inference privacy, improving the empirical estimation of worst-case privacy through crafting adversarial canary records.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.16913v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>stat.ML</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhuohang Li, Andrew Lowy, Jing Liu, Toshiaki Koike-Akino, Kieran Parsons, Bradley Malin, Ye Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ACE-2005-PT: Corpus for Event Extraction in Portuguese</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.16928</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.16928v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Event extraction is an NLP task that commonly involves identifying the central word (trigger) for an event and its associated arguments in text. ACE-2005 is widely recognised as the standard corpus in this field. While other corpora, like PropBank, primarily focus on annotating predicate-argument structure, ACE-2005 provides comprehensive information about the overall event structure and semantics. However, its limited language coverage restricts its usability. This paper introduces ACE-2005-PT, a corpus created by translating ACE-2005 into Portuguese, with European and Brazilian variants. To speed up the process of obtaining ACE-2005-PT, we rely on automatic translators. This, however, poses some challenges related to automatically identifying the correct alignments between multi-word annotations in the original text and in the corresponding translated sentence. To achieve this, we developed an alignment pipeline that incorporates several alignment techniques: lemmatization, fuzzy matching, synonym matching, multiple translations and a BERT-based word aligner. To measure the alignment effectiveness, a subset of annotations from the ACE-2005-PT corpus was manually aligned by a linguist expert. This subset was then compared against our pipeline results which achieved exact and relaxed match scores of 70.55\% and 87.55\% respectively. As a result, we successfully generated a Portuguese version of the ACE-2005 corpus, which has been accepted for publication by LDC.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.16928v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1145/3626772.3657872</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>SIGIR '24: Proceedings of the 47th International ACM SIGIR Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval (2024)</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Lu\'is Filipe Cunha, Purifica\c{c}\~ao Silvano, Ricardo Campos, Al\'ipio Jorge</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Event Extraction for Portuguese: A QA-driven Approach using ACE-2005</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.16932</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.16932v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Event extraction is an Information Retrieval task that commonly consists of identifying the central word for the event (trigger) and the event's arguments. This task has been extensively studied for English but lags behind for Portuguese, partly due to the lack of task-specific annotated corpora. This paper proposes a framework in which two separated BERT-based models were fine-tuned to identify and classify events in Portuguese documents. We decompose this task into two sub-tasks. Firstly, we use a token classification model to detect event triggers. To extract event arguments, we train a Question Answering model that queries the triggers about their corresponding event argument roles. Given the lack of event annotated corpora in Portuguese, we translated the original version of the ACE-2005 dataset (a reference in the field) into Portuguese, producing a new corpus for Portuguese event extraction. To accomplish this, we developed an automatic translation pipeline. Our framework obtains F1 marks of 64.4 for trigger classification and 46.7 for argument classification setting, thus a new state-of-the-art reference for these tasks in Portuguese.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.16932v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1007/9</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Progress in Artificial Intelligence. EPIA 2023. Lecture Notes in Computer Science(), vol 14115. Springer, Cham</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Lu\'is Filipe Cunha, Ricardo Campos, Al\'ipio Jorge</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A longitudinal sentiment analysis of Sinophobia during COVID-19 using large language models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.16942</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.16942v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: The COVID-19 pandemic has exacerbated xenophobia, particularly Sinophobia, leading to widespread discrimination against individuals of Chinese descent. Large language models (LLMs) are pre-trained deep learning models used for natural language processing (NLP) tasks. The ability of LLMs to understand and generate human-like text makes them particularly useful for analysing social media data to detect and evaluate sentiments. We present a sentiment analysis framework utilising LLMs for longitudinal sentiment analysis of the Sinophobic sentiments expressed in X (Twitter) during the COVID-19 pandemic. The results show a significant correlation between the spikes in Sinophobic tweets, Sinophobic sentiments and surges in COVID-19 cases, revealing that the evolution of the pandemic influenced public sentiment and the prevalence of Sinophobic discourse. Furthermore, the sentiment analysis revealed a predominant presence of negative sentiments, such as annoyance and denial, which underscores the impact of political narratives and misinformation shaping public opinion. The lack of empathetic sentiment which was present in previous studies related to COVID-19 highlights the way the political narratives in media viewed the pandemic and how it blamed the Chinese community. Our study highlights the importance of transparent communication in mitigating xenophobic sentiments during global crises.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.16942v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chen Wang, Rohitash Chandra</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Different Victims, Same Layout: Email Visual Similarity Detection for Enhanced Email Protection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.16945</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.16945v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: In the pursuit of an effective spam detection system, the focus has often been on identifying known spam patterns either through rule-based detection systems or machine learning (ML) solutions. However, both systems are susceptible to evasion techniques and zero-day attacks that can be achieved at low cost. Therefore, an email that bypassed the defense system once can do it again in the following days, even though rules are updated or the ML models are retrained. The recurrence of failures to detect emails that exhibit layout similarities to previously undetected spam is concerning for customers and can erode their trust in a company. Our observations show that threat actors reuse email kits extensively and can bypass detection with little effort, for example, by making changes to the content of emails. In this work, we propose an email visual similarity detection approach, named Pisco, to improve the detection capabilities of an email threat defense system. We apply our proof of concept to some real-world samples received from different sources. Our results show that email kits are being reused extensively and visually similar emails are sent to our customers at various time intervals. Therefore, this method could be very helpful in situations where detection features that rely on contextual information and keywords are bypassed, an occurrence our observations show happens frequently.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.16945v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sachin Shukla, Omid Mirzaei</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transient Fault Tolerant Semantic Segmentation for Autonomous Driving</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.16952</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.16952v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Deep learning models are crucial for autonomous vehicle perception, but their reliability is challenged by algorithmic limitations and hardware faults. We address the latter by examining fault-tolerance in semantic segmentation models. Using established hardware fault models, we evaluate existing hardening techniques both in terms of accuracy and uncertainty and introduce ReLUMax, a novel simple activation function designed to enhance resilience against transient faults. ReLUMax integrates seamlessly into existing architectures without time overhead. Our experiments demonstrate that ReLUMax effectively improves robustness, preserving performance and boosting prediction confidence, thus contributing to the development of reliable autonomous driving systems.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.16952v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Leonardo Iurada, Niccol\`o Cavagnero, Fernando Fernandes Dos Santos, Giuseppe Averta, Paolo Rech, Tatiana Tommasi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Discovery of False Data Injection Schemes on Frequency Controllers with Reinforcement Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.16958</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.16958v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: While inverter-based distributed energy resources (DERs) play a crucial role in integrating renewable energy into the power system, they concurrently diminish the grid's system inertia, elevating the risk of frequency instabilities. Furthermore, smart inverters, interfaced via communication networks, pose a potential vulnerability to cyber threats if not diligently managed. To proactively fortify the power grid against sophisticated cyber attacks, we propose to employ reinforcement learning (RL) to identify potential threats and system vulnerabilities. This study concentrates on analyzing adversarial strategies for false data injection, specifically targeting smart inverters involved in primary frequency control. Our findings demonstrate that an RL agent can adeptly discern optimal false data injection methods to manipulate inverter settings, potentially causing catastrophic consequences.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.16958v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Romesh Prasad, Malik Hassanaly, Xiangyu Zhang, Abhijeet Sahu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Future of Open Human Feedback</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.16961</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.16961v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Human feedback on conversations with language language models (LLMs) is central to how these systems learn about the world, improve their capabilities, and are steered toward desirable and safe behaviors. However, this feedback is mostly collected by frontier AI labs and kept behind closed doors. In this work, we bring together interdisciplinary experts to assess the opportunities and challenges to realizing an open ecosystem of human feedback for AI. We first look for successful practices in peer production, open source, and citizen science communities. We then characterize the main challenges for open human feedback. For each, we survey current approaches and offer recommendations. We end by envisioning the components needed to underpin a sustainable and open human feedback ecosystem. In the center of this ecosystem are mutually beneficial feedback loops, between users and specialized models, incentivizing a diverse stakeholders community of model trainers and feedback providers to support a general open feedback pool.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.16961v1</guid>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shachar Don-Yehiya, Ben Burtenshaw, Ramon Fernandez Astudillo, Cailean Osborne, Mimansa Jaiswal, Tzu-Sheng Kuo, Wenting Zhao, Idan Shenfeld, Andi Peng, Mikhail Yurochkin, Atoosa Kasirzadeh, Yangsibo Huang, Tatsunori Hashimoto, Yacine Jernite, Daniel Vila-Suero, Omri Abend, Jennifer Ding, Sara Hooker, Hannah Rose Kirk, Leshem Choshen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UserSumBench: A Benchmark Framework for Evaluating User Summarization Approaches</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.16966</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.16966v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) have shown remarkable capabilities in generating user summaries from a long list of raw user activity data. These summaries capture essential user information such as preferences and interests, and therefore are invaluable for LLM-based personalization applications, such as explainable recommender systems. However, the development of new summarization techniques is hindered by the lack of ground-truth labels, the inherent subjectivity of user summaries, and human evaluation which is often costly and time-consuming. To address these challenges, we introduce \UserSumBench, a benchmark framework designed to facilitate iterative development of LLM-based summarization approaches. This framework offers two key components: (1) A reference-free summary quality metric. We show that this metric is effective and aligned with human preferences across three diverse datasets (MovieLens, Yelp and Amazon Review). (2) A novel robust summarization method that leverages time-hierarchical summarizer and self-critique verifier to produce high-quality summaries while eliminating hallucination. This method serves as a strong baseline for further innovation in summarization techniques.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.16966v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chao Wang, Neo Wu, Lin Ning, Luyang Liu, Jun Xie, Shawn O'Banion, Bradley Green</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MemLong: Memory-Augmented Retrieval for Long Text Modeling</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.16967</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.16967v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Recent advancements in Large Language Models (LLMs) have yielded remarkable success across diverse fields. However, handling long contexts remains a significant challenge for LLMs due to the quadratic time and space complexity of attention mechanisms and the growing memory consumption of the key-value cache during generation. This work introduces MemLong: Memory-Augmented Retrieval for Long Text Generation, a method designed to enhance the capabilities of long-context language modeling by utilizing an external retriever for historical information retrieval. MemLong combines a non-differentiable ``ret-mem'' module with a partially trainable decoder-only language model and introduces a fine-grained, controllable retrieval attention mechanism that leverages semantic-level relevant chunks. Comprehensive evaluations on multiple long-context language modeling benchmarks demonstrate that MemLong consistently outperforms other state-of-the-art LLMs. More importantly, MemLong can extend the context length on a single 3090 GPU from 4k up to 80k. Our code is available at https://github.com/Bui1dMySea/MemLong</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.16967v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Weijie Liu, Zecheng Tang, Juntao Li, Kehai Chen, Min Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Technical Report of HelixFold3 for Biomolecular Structure Prediction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.16975</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.16975v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: The AlphaFold series has transformed protein structure prediction with remarkable accuracy, often matching experimental methods. AlphaFold2, AlphaFold-Multimer, and the latest AlphaFold3 represent significant strides in predicting single protein chains, protein complexes, and biomolecular structures. While AlphaFold2 and AlphaFold-Multimer are open-sourced, facilitating rapid and reliable predictions, AlphaFold3 remains partially accessible through a limited online server and has not been open-sourced, restricting further development. To address these challenges, the PaddleHelix team is developing HelixFold3, aiming to replicate AlphaFold3's capabilities. Using insights from previous models and extensive datasets, HelixFold3 achieves an accuracy comparable to AlphaFold3 in predicting the structures of conventional ligands, nucleic acids, and proteins. The initial release of HelixFold3 is available as open source on GitHub for academic research, promising to advance biomolecular research and accelerate discoveries. We also provide online service at PaddleHelix website at https://paddlehelix.baidu.com/app/all/helixfold3/forecast.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.16975v1</guid>
      <category>q-bio.BM</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Lihang Liu, Shanzhuo Zhang, Yang Xue, Xianbin Ye, Kunrui Zhu, Yuxin Li, Yang Liu, Xiaonan Zhang, Xiaomin Fang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Training Ultra Long Context Language Model with Fully Pipelined Distributed Transformer</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.16978</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.16978v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) with long context capabilities are integral to complex tasks in natural language processing and computational biology, such as text generation and protein sequence analysis. However, training LLMs directly on extremely long contexts demands considerable GPU resources and increased memory, leading to higher costs and greater complexity. Alternative approaches that introduce long context capabilities via downstream finetuning or adaptations impose significant design limitations. In this paper, we propose Fully Pipelined Distributed Transformer (FPDT) for efficiently training long-context LLMs with extreme hardware efficiency. For GPT and Llama models, we achieve a 16x increase in sequence length that can be trained on the same hardware compared to current state-of-the-art solutions. With our dedicated sequence chunk pipeline design, we can now train 8B LLM with 2 million sequence length on only 4 GPUs, while also maintaining over 55% of MFU. Our proposed FPDT is agnostic to existing training techniques and is proven to work efficiently across different LLM models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.16978v1</guid>
      <category>cs.DC</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jinghan Yao, Sam Ade Jacobs, Masahiro Tanaka, Olatunji Ruwase, Aamir Shafi, Hari Subramoni, Dhabaleswar K. Panda</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Safety Layers of Aligned Large Language Models: The Key to LLM Security</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.17003</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.17003v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Aligned LLMs are highly secure, capable of recognizing and refusing to answer malicious questions. However, the role of internal parameters in maintaining this security is not well understood, further these models are vulnerable to security degradation when fine-tuned with non-malicious backdoor data or normal data. To address these challenges, our work uncovers the mechanism behind security in aligned LLMs at the parameter level, identifying a small set of contiguous layers in the middle of the model that are crucial for distinguishing malicious queries from normal ones, referred to as "safety layers." We first confirm the existence of these safety layers by analyzing variations in input vectors within the model's internal layers. Additionally, we leverage the over-rejection phenomenon and parameters scaling analysis to precisely locate the safety layers. Building on this understanding, we propose a novel fine-tuning approach, Safely Partial-Parameter Fine-Tuning (SPPFT), that fixes the gradient of the safety layers during fine-tuning to address the security degradation. Our experiments demonstrate that this approach significantly preserves model security while maintaining performance and reducing computational resources compared to full fine-tuning.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.17003v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shen Li, Liuyi Yao, Lan Zhang, Yaliang Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving Time Series Classification with Representation Soft Label Smoothing</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.17010</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.17010v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Previous research has indicated that deep neural network based models for time series classification (TSC) tasks are prone to overfitting. This issue can be mitigated by employing strategies that prevent the model from becoming overly confident in its predictions, such as label smoothing and confidence penalty. Building upon the concept of label smoothing, we propose a novel approach to generate more reliable soft labels, which we refer to as representation soft label smoothing. We apply label smoothing, confidence penalty, and our method representation soft label smoothing to several TSC models and compare their performance with baseline method which only uses hard labels for training. Our results demonstrate that the use of these enhancement techniques yields competitive results compared to the baseline method. Importantly, our method demonstrates strong performance across models with varying structures and complexities.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.17010v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hengyi Ma, Weitong Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Disease Classification and Impact of Pretrained Deep Convolution Neural Networks on Diverse Medical Imaging Datasets across Imaging Modalities</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.17011</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.17011v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Imaging techniques such as Chest X-rays, whole slide images, and optical coherence tomography serve as the initial screening and detection for a wide variety of medical pulmonary and ophthalmic conditions respectively. This paper investigates the intricacies of using pretrained deep convolutional neural networks with transfer learning across diverse medical imaging datasets with varying modalities for binary and multiclass classification. We conducted a comprehensive performance analysis with ten network architectures and model families each with pretraining and random initialization. Our finding showed that the use of pretrained models as fixed feature extractors yields poor performance irrespective of the datasets. Contrary, histopathology microscopy whole slide images have better performance. It is also found that deeper and more complex architectures did not necessarily result in the best performance. This observation implies that the improvements in ImageNet are not parallel to the medical imaging tasks. Within a medical domain, the performance of the network architectures varies within model families with shifts in datasets. This indicates that the performance of models within a specific modality may not be conclusive for another modality within the same domain. This study provides a deeper understanding of the applications of deep learning techniques in medical imaging and highlights the impact of pretrained networks across different medical imaging datasets under five different experimental settings.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.17011v1</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jutika Borah, Kumaresh Sarmah, Hidam Kumarjit Singh</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Self-Consistency: Leveraging Reasoning Paths for Efficient LLM Sampling</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.17017</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.17017v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Self-Consistency (SC) is a widely used method to mitigate hallucinations in Large Language Models (LLMs) by sampling the LLM multiple times and outputting the most frequent solution. Despite its benefits, SC results in significant computational costs proportional to the number of samples generated. Previous early-stopping approaches, such as Early Stopping Self Consistency and Adaptive Consistency, have aimed to reduce these costs by considering output consistency, but they do not analyze the quality of the reasoning paths (RPs) themselves. To address this issue, we propose Reasoning-Aware Self-Consistency (RASC), an innovative early-stopping framework that dynamically adjusts the number of sample generations by considering both the output answer and the RPs from Chain of Thought (CoT) prompting. RASC assigns confidence scores sequentially to the generated samples, stops when certain criteria are met, and then employs weighted majority voting to optimize sample usage and enhance answer reliability. We comprehensively test RASC with multiple LLMs across varied QA datasets. RASC outperformed existing methods and significantly reduces sample usage by an average of 80% while maintaining or improving accuracy up to 5% compared to the original SC</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.17017v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Guangya Wan, Yuqi Wu, Jie Chen, Sheng Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Survey of the Self Supervised Learning Mechanisms for Vision Transformers</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.17059</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.17059v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Deep supervised learning models require high volume of labeled data to attain sufficiently good results. Although, the practice of gathering and annotating such big data is costly and laborious. Recently, the application of self supervised learning (SSL) in vision tasks has gained significant attention. The intuition behind SSL is to exploit the synchronous relationships within the data as a form of self-supervision, which can be versatile. In the current big data era, most of the data is unlabeled, and the success of SSL thus relies in finding ways to improve this vast amount of unlabeled data available. Thus its better for deep learning algorithms to reduce reliance on human supervision and instead focus on self-supervision based on the inherent relationships within the data. With the advent of ViTs, which have achieved remarkable results in computer vision, it is crucial to explore and understand the various SSL mechanisms employed for training these models specifically in scenarios where there is less label data available. In this survey we thus develop a comprehensive taxonomy of systematically classifying the SSL techniques based upon their representations and pre-training tasks being applied. Additionally, we discuss the motivations behind SSL, review popular pre-training tasks, and highlight the challenges and advancements in this field. Furthermore, we present a comparative analysis of different SSL methods, evaluate their strengths and limitations, and identify potential avenues for future research.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.17059v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Asifullah Khan, Anabia Sohail, Mustansar Fiaz, Mehdi Hassan, Tariq Habib Afridi, Sibghat Ullah Marwat, Farzeen Munir, Safdar Ali, Hannan Naseem, Muhammad Zaigham Zaheer, Kamran Ali, Tangina Sultana, Ziaurrehman Tanoli, Naeem Akhter</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Instant Adversarial Purification with Adversarial Consistency Distillation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.17064</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.17064v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Neural networks, despite their remarkable performance in widespread applications, including image classification, are also known to be vulnerable to subtle adversarial noise. Although some diffusion-based purification methods have been proposed, for example, DiffPure, those methods are time-consuming. In this paper, we propose One Step Control Purification (OSCP), a diffusion-based purification model that can purify the adversarial image in one Neural Function Evaluation (NFE) in diffusion models. We use Latent Consistency Model (LCM) and ControlNet for our one-step purification. OSCP is computationally friendly and time efficient compared to other diffusion-based purification methods; we achieve defense success rate of 74.19\% on ImageNet, only requiring 0.1s for each purification. Moreover, there is a fundamental incongruence between consistency distillation and adversarial perturbation. To address this ontological dissonance, we propose Gaussian Adversarial Noise Distillation (GAND), a novel consistency distillation framework that facilitates a more nuanced reconciliation of the latent space dynamics, effectively bridging the natural and adversarial manifolds. Our experiments show that the GAND does not need a Full Fine Tune (FFT); PEFT, e.g., LoRA is sufficient.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.17064v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chun Tong Lei, Hon Ming Yam, Zhongliang Guo, Chun Pong Lau</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FissionVAE: Federated Non-IID Image Generation with Latent Space and Decoder Decomposition</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.17090</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.17090v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Federated learning is a machine learning paradigm that enables decentralized clients to collaboratively learn a shared model while keeping all the training data local. While considerable research has focused on federated image generation, particularly Generative Adversarial Networks, Variational Autoencoders have received less attention. In this paper, we address the challenges of non-IID (independently and identically distributed) data environments featuring multiple groups of images of different types. Specifically, heterogeneous data distributions can lead to difficulties in maintaining a consistent latent space and can also result in local generators with disparate texture features being blended during aggregation. We introduce a novel approach, FissionVAE, which decomposes the latent space and constructs decoder branches tailored to individual client groups. This method allows for customized learning that aligns with the unique data distributions of each group. Additionally, we investigate the incorporation of hierarchical VAE architectures and demonstrate the use of heterogeneous decoder architectures within our model. We also explore strategies for setting the latent prior distributions to enhance the decomposition process. To evaluate our approach, we assemble two composite datasets: the first combines MNIST and FashionMNIST; the second comprises RGB datasets of cartoon and human faces, wild animals, marine vessels, and remote sensing images of Earth. Our experiments demonstrate that FissionVAE greatly improves generation quality on these datasets compared to baseline federated VAE models.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.17090v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chen Hu, Jingjing Deng, Xianghua Xie, Xiaoke Ma</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the User: An Intent-Based Ranking Dataset</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.17103</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.17103v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: As information retrieval systems continue to evolve, accurate evaluation and benchmarking of these systems become pivotal. Web search datasets, such as MS MARCO, primarily provide short keyword queries without accompanying intent or descriptions, posing a challenge in comprehending the underlying information need. This paper proposes an approach to augmenting such datasets to annotate informative query descriptions, with a focus on two prominent benchmark datasets: TREC-DL-21 and TREC-DL-22. Our methodology involves utilizing state-of-the-art LLMs to analyze and comprehend the implicit intent within individual queries from benchmark datasets. By extracting key semantic elements, we construct detailed and contextually rich descriptions for these queries. To validate the generated query descriptions, we employ crowdsourcing as a reliable means of obtaining diverse human perspectives on the accuracy and informativeness of the descriptions. This information can be used as an evaluation set for tasks such as ranking, query rewriting, or others.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.17103v1</guid>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Abhijit Anand, Jurek Leonhardt, V Venktesh, Avishek Anand</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring User Acceptance Of Portable Intelligent Personal Assistants: A Hybrid Approach Using PLS-SEM And fsQCA</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.17119</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.17119v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: This research explores the factors driving user acceptance of Rabbit R1, a newly developed portable intelligent personal assistant (PIPA) that aims to redefine user interaction and control. The study extends the technology acceptance model (TAM) by incorporating artificial intelligence-specific factors (conversational intelligence, task intelligence, and perceived naturalness), user interface design factors (simplicity in information design and visual aesthetics), and user acceptance and loyalty. Using a purposive sampling method, we gathered data from 824 users in the US and analyzed the sample through partial least squares structural equation modeling (PLS-SEM) and fuzzy set qualitative comparative analysis (fsQCA). The findings reveal that all hypothesized relationships, including both direct and indirect effects, are supported. Additionally, fsQCA supports the PLS-SEM findings and identifies three configurations leading to high and low user acceptance. This research enriches the literature and provides valuable insights for system designers and marketers of PIPAs, guiding strategic decisions to foster widespread adoption and long-term engagement.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.17119v1</guid>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Gustave Florentin Nkoulou Mvondo, Ben Niu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Controllable Edge-Type-Specific Interpretation in Multi-Relational Graph Neural Networks for Drug Response Prediction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.17129</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.17129v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Graph Neural Networks have been widely applied in critical decision-making areas that demand interpretable predictions, leading to the flourishing development of interpretability algorithms. However, current graph interpretability algorithms tend to emphasize generality and often overlook biological significance, thereby limiting their applicability in predicting cancer drug responses. In this paper, we propose a novel post-hoc interpretability algorithm for cancer drug response prediction, CETExplainer, which incorporates a controllable edge-type-specific weighting mechanism. It considers the mutual information between subgraphs and predictions, proposing a structural scoring approach to provide fine-grained, biologically meaningful explanations for predictive models. We also introduce a method for constructing ground truth based on real-world datasets to quantitatively evaluate the proposed interpretability algorithm. Empirical analysis on the real-world dataset demonstrates that CETExplainer achieves superior stability and improves explanation quality compared to leading algorithms, thereby offering a robust and insightful tool for cancer drug prediction.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.17129v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiaodi Li, Jianfeng Gui, Qian Gao, Haoyuan Shi, Zhenyu Yue</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VQ4DiT: Efficient Post-Training Vector Quantization for Diffusion Transformers</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.17131</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.17131v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: The Diffusion Transformers Models (DiTs) have transitioned the network architecture from traditional UNets to transformers, demonstrating exceptional capabilities in image generation. Although DiTs have been widely applied to high-definition video generation tasks, their large parameter size hinders inference on edge devices. Vector quantization (VQ) can decompose model weight into a codebook and assignments, allowing extreme weight quantization and significantly reducing memory usage. In this paper, we propose VQ4DiT, a fast post-training vector quantization method for DiTs. We found that traditional VQ methods calibrate only the codebook without calibrating the assignments. This leads to weight sub-vectors being incorrectly assigned to the same assignment, providing inconsistent gradients to the codebook and resulting in a suboptimal result. To address this challenge, VQ4DiT calculates the candidate assignment set for each weight sub-vector based on Euclidean distance and reconstructs the sub-vector based on the weighted average. Then, using the zero-data and block-wise calibration method, the optimal assignment from the set is efficiently selected while calibrating the codebook. VQ4DiT quantizes a DiT XL/2 model on a single NVIDIA A100 GPU within 20 minutes to 5 hours depending on the different quantization settings. Experiments show that VQ4DiT establishes a new state-of-the-art in model size and performance trade-offs, quantizing weights to 2-bit precision while retaining acceptable image generation quality.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.17131v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Juncan Deng, Shuaiting Li, Zeyu Wang, Hong Gu, Kedong Xu, Kejie Huang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leveraging Digital Twin Technologies for Public Space Protection and Vulnerability Assessment</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.17136</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.17136v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Over the recent years, the protection of the so-called `soft-targets', i.e. locations easily accessible by the general public with relatively low, though, security measures, has emerged as a rather challenging and increasingly important issue. The complexity and seriousness of this security threat growths nowadays exponentially, due to the emergence of new advanced technologies (e.g. Artificial Intelligence (AI), Autonomous Vehicles (AVs), 3D printing, etc.); especially when it comes to large-scale, popular and diverse public spaces. In this paper, a novel Digital Twin-as-a-Security-Service (DTaaSS) architecture is introduced for holistically and significantly enhancing the protection of public spaces (e.g. metro stations, leisure sites, urban squares, etc.). The proposed framework combines a Digital Twin (DT) conceptualization with additional cutting-edge technologies, including Internet of Things (IoT), cloud computing, Big Data analytics and AI. In particular, DTaaSS comprises a holistic, real-time, large-scale, comprehensive and data-driven security solution for the efficient/robust protection of public spaces, supporting: a) data collection and analytics, b) area monitoring/control and proactive threat detection, c) incident/attack prediction, and d) quantitative and data-driven vulnerability assessment. Overall, the designed architecture exhibits increased potential in handling complex, hybrid and combined threats over large, critical and popular soft-targets. The applicability and robustness of DTaaSS is discussed in detail against representative and diverse real-world application scenarios, including complex attacks to: a) a metro station, b) a leisure site, and c) a cathedral square.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.17136v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Artemis Stefanidou, Jorgen Cani, Thomas Papadopoulos, Panagiotis Radoglou-Grammatikis, Panagiotis Sarigiannidis, Iraklis Varlamis, Georgios Th. Papadopoulos</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards Hyper-parameter-free Federated Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.17145</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.17145v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: The adaptive synchronization techniques in federated learning (FL) for scaled global model updates show superior performance over the vanilla federated averaging (FedAvg) scheme. However, existing methods employ additional tunable hyperparameters on the server to determine the scaling factor. A contrasting approach is automated scaling analogous to tuning-free step-size schemes in stochastic gradient descent (SGD) methods, which offer competitive convergence rates and exhibit good empirical performance. In this work, we introduce two algorithms for automated scaling of global model updates. In our first algorithm, we establish that a descent-ensuring step-size regime at the clients ensures descent for the server objective. We show that such a scheme enables linear convergence for strongly convex federated objectives. Our second algorithm shows that the average of objective values of sampled clients is a practical and effective substitute for the objective function value at the server required for computing the scaling factor, whose computation is otherwise not permitted. Our extensive empirical results show that the proposed methods perform at par or better than the popular federated learning algorithms for both convex and non-convex problems. Our work takes a step towards designing hyper-parameter-free federated learning.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.17145v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>math.OC</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator> Geetika, Drishya Uniyal, Bapi Chatterjee</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Look, Compare, Decide: Alleviating Hallucination in Large Vision-Language Models via Multi-View Multi-Path Reasoning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.17150</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.17150v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Recently, Large Vision-Language Models (LVLMs) have demonstrated impressive capabilities in multi-modal context comprehension. However, they still suffer from hallucination problems referring to generating inconsistent outputs with the image content. To mitigate hallucinations, previous studies mainly focus on retraining LVLMs with custom datasets. Although effective, they inherently come with additional computational costs. In this paper, we propose a training-free framework, \textbf{MVP}, that aims to reduce hallucinations by making the most of the innate capabilities of the LVLMs via \textbf{M}ulti-\textbf{V}iew Multi-\textbf{P}ath Reasoning. Specifically, we first devise a multi-view information-seeking strategy to thoroughly perceive the comprehensive information in the image, which enriches the general global information captured by the original vision encoder in LVLMs. Furthermore, during the answer decoding, we observe that the occurrence of hallucinations has a strong correlation with the certainty of the answer tokens. Thus, we propose multi-path reasoning for each information view to quantify and aggregate the certainty scores for each potential answer among multiple decoding paths and finally decide the output answer. By fully grasping the information in the image and carefully considering the certainty of the potential answers when decoding, our MVP can effectively reduce hallucinations in LVLMs.The extensive experiments verify that our proposed MVP significantly mitigates the hallucination problem across four well-known LVLMs. The source code is available at: \url{https://github.com/GasolSun36/MVP}.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.17150v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xiaoye Qu, Jiashuo Sun, Wei Wei, Yu Cheng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deep Feature Embedding for Tabular Data</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.17162</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.17162v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Tabular data learning has extensive applications in deep learning but its existing embedding techniques are limited in numerical and categorical features such as the inability to capture complex relationships and engineering. This paper proposes a novel deep embedding framework with leverages lightweight deep neural networks to generate effective feature embeddings for tabular data in machine learning research. For numerical features, a two-step feature expansion and deep transformation technique is used to capture copious semantic information. For categorical features, a unique identification vector for each entity is referred by a compact lookup table with a parameterized deep embedding function to uniform the embedding size dimensions, and transformed into a embedding vector using deep neural network. Experiments are conducted on real-world datasets for performance evaluation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.17162v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuqian Wu, Hengyi Luo, Raymond S. T. Lee</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Codec Does Matter: Exploring the Semantic Shortcoming of Codec for Audio Language Model</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.17175</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.17175v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Recent advancements in audio generation have been significantly propelled by the capabilities of Large Language Models (LLMs). The existing research on audio LLM has primarily focused on enhancing the architecture and scale of audio language models, as well as leveraging larger datasets, and generally, acoustic codecs, such as EnCodec, are used for audio tokenization. However, these codecs were originally designed for audio compression, which may lead to suboptimal performance in the context of audio LLM. Our research aims to address the shortcomings of current audio LLM codecs, particularly their challenges in maintaining semantic integrity in generated audio. For instance, existing methods like VALL-E, which condition acoustic token generation on text transcriptions, often suffer from content inaccuracies and elevated word error rates (WER) due to semantic misinterpretations of acoustic tokens, resulting in word skipping and errors. To overcome these issues, we propose a straightforward yet effective approach called X-Codec. X-Codec incorporates semantic features from a pre-trained semantic encoder before the Residual Vector Quantization (RVQ) stage and introduces a semantic reconstruction loss after RVQ. By enhancing the semantic ability of the codec, X-Codec significantly reduces WER in speech synthesis tasks and extends these benefits to non-speech applications, including music and sound generation. Our experiments in text-to-speech, music continuation, and text-to-sound tasks demonstrate that integrating semantic information substantially improves the overall performance of language models in audio generation. Our code and demo are available (Demo: https://x-codec-audio.github.io Code: https://github.com/zhenye234/xcodec)</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.17175v1</guid>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhen Ye, Peiwen Sun, Jiahe Lei, Hongzhan Lin, Xu Tan, Zheqi Dai, Qiuqiang Kong, Jianyi Chen, Jiahao Pan, Qifeng Liu, Yike Guo, Wei Xue</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Causal Reasoning in Software Quality Assurance: A Systematic Review</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.17183</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.17183v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Context: Software Quality Assurance (SQA) is a fundamental part of software engineering to ensure stakeholders that software products work as expected after release in operation. Machine Learning (ML) has proven to be able to boost SQA activities and contribute to the development of quality software systems. In this context, Causal Reasoning is gaining increasing interest as a methodology to solve some of the current ML limitations. It aims to go beyond a purely data-driven approach by exploiting the use of causality for more effective SQA strategies. Objective: Provide a broad and detailed overview of the use of causal reasoning for SQA activities, in order to support researchers to access this research field, identifying room for application, main challenges and research opportunities. Methods: A systematic literature review of causal reasoning in the SQA research area. Scientific papers have been searched, classified, and analyzed according to established guidelines for software engineering secondary studies. Results: Results highlight the primary areas within SQA where causal reasoning has been applied, the predominant methodologies used, and the level of maturity of the proposed solutions. Fault localization is the activity where causal reasoning is more exploited, especially in the web services/microservices domain, but other tasks like testing are rapidly gaining popularity. Both causal inference and causal discovery are exploited, with the Pearl's graphical formulation of causality being preferred, likely due to its intuitiveness. Tools to favour their application are appearing at a fast pace - most of them after 2021. Conclusions: The findings show that causal reasoning is a valuable means for SQA tasks with respect to multiple quality attributes, especially during V&amp;V, evolution and maintenance to ensure reliability, while it is not yet fully exploited for phases like ...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.17183v1</guid>
      <category>cs.SE</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Luca Giamattei, Antonio Guerriero, Roberto Pietrantuono, Stefano Russo</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>"Benefit Game: Alien Seaweed Swarms" -- Real-time Gamification of Digital Seaweed Ecology</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.17186</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.17186v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: "Benefit Game: Alien Seaweed Swarms" combines artificial life art and interactive game with installation to explore the impact of human activity on fragile seaweed ecosystems. The project aims to promote ecological consciousness by creating a balance in digital seaweed ecologies. Inspired by the real species "Laminaria saccharina", the author employs Procedural Content Generation via Machine Learning technology to generate variations of virtual seaweeds and symbiotic fungi. The audience can explore the consequences of human activities through gameplay and observe the ecosystem's feedback on the benefits and risks of seaweed aquaculture. This Benefit Game offers dynamic and real-time responsive artificial seaweed ecosystems for an interactive experience that enhances ecological consciousness.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.17186v1</guid>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.SY</category>
      <category>eess.SY</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Dan-Lu Fei, Zi-Wei Wu, Kang Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI-Driven Intrusion Detection Systems (IDS) on the ROAD dataset: A Comparative Analysis for automotive Controller Area Network (CAN)</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.17235</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.17235v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: The integration of digital devices in modern vehicles has revolutionized automotive technology, enhancing safety and the overall driving experience. The Controller Area Network (CAN) bus is a central system for managing in-vehicle communication between the electronic control units (ECUs). However, the CAN protocol poses security challenges due to inherent vulnerabilities, lacking encryption and authentication, which, combined with an expanding attack surface, necessitates robust security measures. In response to this challenge, numerous Intrusion Detection Systems (IDS) have been developed and deployed. Nonetheless, an open, comprehensive, and realistic dataset to test the effectiveness of such IDSs remains absent in the existing literature. This paper addresses this gap by considering the latest ROAD dataset, containing stealthy and sophisticated injections. The methodology involves dataset labelling and the implementation of both state-of-the-art deep learning models and traditional machine learning models to show the discrepancy in performance between the datasets most commonly used in the literature and the ROAD dataset, a more realistic alternative.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.17235v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Lorenzo Guerra, Linhan Xu, Pavlo Mozharovskyi, Paolo Bellavista, Thomas Chapuis, Guillaume Duc, Van-Tam Nguyen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Abstracted Gaussian Prototypes for One-Shot Concept Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.17251</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.17251v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: We introduce a cluster-based generative image segmentation framework to encode higher-level representations of visual concepts based on one-shot learning inspired by the Omniglot Challenge. The inferred parameters of each component of a Gaussian Mixture Model (GMM) represent a distinct topological subpart of a visual concept. Sampling new data from these parameters generates augmented subparts to build a more robust prototype for each concept, i.e., the Abstracted Gaussian Prototype (AGP). This framework addresses one-shot classification tasks using a cognitively-inspired similarity metric and addresses one-shot generative tasks through a novel AGP-VAE pipeline employing variational autoencoders (VAEs) to generate new class variants. Results from human judges reveal that the generative pipeline produces novel examples and classes of visual concepts that are broadly indistinguishable from those made by humans. The proposed framework leads to impressive but not state-of-the-art classification accuracy; thus, the contribution is two-fold: 1) the system is uniquely low in theoretical and computational complexity and operates in a completely standalone manner compared while existing approaches draw heavily on pre-training or knowledge engineering; and 2) in contrast with competing neural network models, the AGP approach addresses the importance of breadth of task capability emphasized in the Omniglot challenge (i.e., successful performance on generative tasks). These two points are critical as we advance toward an understanding of how learning/reasoning systems can produce viable, robust, and flexible concepts based on literally nothing more than a single example.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.17251v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chelsea Zou, Kenneth J. Kurtz</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VisionTS: Visual Masked Autoencoders Are Free-Lunch Zero-Shot Time Series Forecasters</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.17253</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.17253v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Foundation models have emerged as a promising approach in time series forecasting (TSF). Existing approaches either fine-tune large language models (LLMs) or build large-scale time-series datasets to develop TSF foundation models. However, these methods face challenges due to the severe cross-domain gap or in-domain heterogeneity. In this paper, we explore a new road to building a TSF foundation model from rich and high-quality natural images, based on the intrinsic similarities between images and time series. To bridge the gap between the two domains, we reformulate the TSF task as an image reconstruction task, which is further processed by a visual masked autoencoder (MAE) self-supervised pre-trained on the ImageNet dataset. Surprisingly, without further adaptation in the time-series domain, the proposed VisionTS could achieve superior zero-shot forecasting performance compared to existing TSF foundation models. With minimal fine-tuning, VisionTS could further improve the forecasting and achieve state-of-the-art performance in most cases. These findings suggest that visual models could be a free lunch for TSF and highlight the potential for future cross-domain research between computer vision and TSF. Our code is publicly available at https://github.com/Keytoyze/VisionTS.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.17253v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mouxiang Chen, Lefei Shen, Zhuo Li, Xiaoyun Joy Wang, Jianling Sun, Chenghao Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UrBench: A Comprehensive Benchmark for Evaluating Large Multimodal Models in Multi-View Urban Scenarios</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.17267</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.17267v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Recent evaluations of Large Multimodal Models (LMMs) have explored their capabilities in various domains, with only few benchmarks specifically focusing on urban environments. Moreover, existing urban benchmarks have been limited to evaluating LMMs with basic region-level urban tasks under singular views, leading to incomplete evaluations of LMMs' abilities in urban environments. To address these issues, we present UrBench, a comprehensive benchmark designed for evaluating LMMs in complex multi-view urban scenarios. UrBench contains 11.6K meticulously curated questions at both region-level and role-level that cover 4 task dimensions: Geo-Localization, Scene Reasoning, Scene Understanding, and Object Understanding, totaling 14 task types. In constructing UrBench, we utilize data from existing datasets and additionally collect data from 11 cities, creating new annotations using a cross-view detection-matching method. With these images and annotations, we then integrate LMM-based, rule-based, and human-based methods to construct large-scale high-quality questions. Our evaluations on 21 LMMs show that current LMMs struggle in the urban environments in several aspects. Even the best performing GPT-4o lags behind humans in most tasks, ranging from simple tasks such as counting to complex tasks such as orientation, localization and object attribute recognition, with an average performance gap of 17.4%. Our benchmark also reveals that LMMs exhibit inconsistent behaviors with different urban views, especially with respect to understanding cross-view relations. UrBench datasets and benchmark results will be publicly available at https://opendatalab.github.io/UrBench/.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.17267v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Baichuan Zhou, Haote Yang, Dairong Chen, Junyan Ye, Tianyi Bai, Jinhua Yu, Songyang Zhang, Dahua Lin, Conghui He, Weijia Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stationary Policies are Optimal in Risk-averse Total-reward MDPs with EVaR</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.17286</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.17286v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Optimizing risk-averse objectives in discounted MDPs is challenging because most models do not admit direct dynamic programming equations and require complex history-dependent policies. In this paper, we show that the risk-averse {\em total reward criterion}, under the Entropic Risk Measure (ERM) and Entropic Value at Risk (EVaR) risk measures, can be optimized by a stationary policy, making it simple to analyze, interpret, and deploy. We propose exponential value iteration, policy iteration, and linear programming to compute optimal policies. In comparison with prior work, our results only require the relatively mild condition of transient MDPs and allow for {\em both} positive and negative rewards. Our results indicate that the total reward criterion may be preferable to the discounted criterion in a broad range of risk-averse reinforcement learning domains.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.17286v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Xihong Su, Marek Petrik, Julien Grand-Cl\'ement</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating the discovery of steady-states of planetary interior dynamics with machine learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.17298</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.17298v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Simulating mantle convection often requires reaching a computationally expensive steady-state, crucial for deriving scaling laws for thermal and dynamical flow properties and benchmarking numerical solutions. The strong temperature dependence of the rheology of mantle rocks causes viscosity variations of several orders of magnitude, leading to a slow-evolving stagnant lid where heat conduction dominates, overlying a rapidly-evolving and strongly convecting region. Time-stepping methods, while effective for fluids with constant viscosity, are hindered by the Courant criterion, which restricts the time step based on the system's maximum velocity and grid size. Consequently, achieving steady-state requires a large number of time steps due to the disparate time scales governing the stagnant and convecting regions.
  We present a concept for accelerating mantle convection simulations using machine learning. We generate a dataset of 128 two-dimensional simulations with mixed basal and internal heating, and pressure- and temperature-dependent viscosity. We train a feedforward neural network on 97 simulations to predict steady-state temperature profiles. These can then be used to initialize numerical time stepping methods for different simulation parameters. Compared to typical initializations, the number of time steps required to reach steady-state is reduced by a median factor of 3.75. The benefit of this method lies in requiring very few simulations to train on, providing a solution with no prediction error as we initialize a numerical method, and posing minimal computational overhead at inference time. We demonstrate the effectiveness of our approach and discuss the potential implications for accelerated simulations for advancing mantle convection research.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.17298v1</guid>
      <category>physics.flu-dyn</category>
      <category>astro-ph.EP</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Siddhant Agarwal, Nicola Tosi, Christian H\"uttig, David S. Greenberg, Ali Can Bekar</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hybridizing Base-Line 2D-CNN Model with Cat Swarm Optimization for Enhanced Advanced Persistent Threat Detection</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.17307</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.17307v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: In the realm of cyber-security, detecting Advanced Persistent Threats (APTs) remains a formidable challenge due to their stealthy and sophisticated nature. This research paper presents an innovative approach that leverages Convolutional Neural Networks (CNNs) with a 2D baseline model, enhanced by the cutting-edge Cat Swarm Optimization (CSO) algorithm, to significantly improve APT detection accuracy. By seamlessly integrating the 2D-CNN baseline model with CSO, we unlock the potential for unprecedented accuracy and efficiency in APT detection. The results unveil an impressive accuracy score of $98.4\%$, marking a significant enhancement in APT detection across various attack stages, illuminating a path forward in combating these relentless and sophisticated threats.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.17307v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.NI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ali M. Bakhiet, Salah A. Aly</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fair Best Arm Identification with Fixed Confidence</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.17313</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.17313v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: In this work, we present a novel framework for Best Arm Identification (BAI) under fairness constraints, a setting that we refer to as \textit{F-BAI} (fair BAI). Unlike traditional BAI, which solely focuses on identifying the optimal arm with minimal sample complexity, F-BAI also includes a set of fairness constraints. These constraints impose a lower limit on the selection rate of each arm and can be either model-agnostic or model-dependent. For this setting, we establish an instance-specific sample complexity lower bound and analyze the \textit{price of fairness}, quantifying how fairness impacts sample complexity. Based on the sample complexity lower bound, we propose F-TaS, an algorithm provably matching the sample complexity lower bound, while ensuring that the fairness constraints are satisfied. Numerical results, conducted using both a synthetic model and a practical wireless scheduling application, show the efficiency of F-TaS in minimizing the sample complexity while achieving low fairness violations.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.17313v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Alessio Russo, Filippo Vannella</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigating Neuron Ablation in Attention Heads: The Case for Peak Activation Centering</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.17322</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.17322v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: The use of transformer-based models is growing rapidly throughout society. With this growth, it is important to understand how they work, and in particular, how the attention mechanisms represent concepts. Though there are many interpretability methods, many look at models through their neuronal activations, which are poorly understood. We describe different lenses through which to view neuron activations, and investigate the effectiveness in language models and vision transformers through various methods of neural ablation: zero ablation, mean ablation, activation resampling, and a novel approach we term 'peak ablation'. Through experimental analysis, we find that in different regimes and models, each method can offer the lowest degradation of model performance compared to other methods, with resampling usually causing the most significant performance deterioration. We make our code available at https://github.com/nickypro/investigating-ablation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.17322v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Nicholas Pochinkov, Ben Pasero, Skylar Shibayama</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modularity in Transformers: Investigating Neuron Separability &amp; Specialization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.17324</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.17324v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Transformer models are increasingly prevalent in various applications, yet our understanding of their internal workings remains limited. This paper investigates the modularity and task specialization of neurons within transformer architectures, focusing on both vision (ViT) and language (Mistral 7B) models. Using a combination of selective pruning and MoEfication clustering techniques, we analyze the overlap and specialization of neurons across different tasks and data subsets. Our findings reveal evidence of task-specific neuron clusters, with varying degrees of overlap between related tasks. We observe that neuron importance patterns persist to some extent even in randomly initialized models, suggesting an inherent structure that training refines. Additionally, we find that neuron clusters identified through MoEfication correspond more strongly to task-specific neurons in earlier and later layers of the models. This work contributes to a more nuanced understanding of transformer internals and offers insights into potential avenues for improving model interpretability and efficiency.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.17324v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Nicholas Pochinkov, Thomas Jones, Mohammed Rashidur Rahman</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>rerankers: A Lightweight Python Library to Unify Ranking Methods</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.17344</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.17344v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: This paper presents rerankers, a Python library which provides an easy-to-use interface to the most commonly used re-ranking approaches. Re-ranking is an integral component of many retrieval pipelines; however, there exist numerous approaches to it, relying on different implementation methods. \texttt{rerankers} unifies these methods into a single user-friendly interface, allowing practitioners and researchers alike to explore different methods while only changing a single line of Python code. Moreover ,rerankers ensures that its implementations are done with the fewest dependencies possible, and re-uses the original implementation whenever possible, guaranteeing that our simplified interface results in no performance degradation compared to more complex ones. The full source code and list of supported models are updated regularly and available at https://github.com/answerdotai/rerankers.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.17344v1</guid>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Benjamin Clavi\'e</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AASIST3: KAN-Enhanced AASIST Speech Deepfake Detection using SSL Features and Additional Regularization for the ASVspoof 2024 Challenge</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.17352</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.17352v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Automatic Speaker Verification (ASV) systems, which identify speakers based on their voice characteristics, have numerous applications, such as user authentication in financial transactions, exclusive access control in smart devices, and forensic fraud detection. However, the advancement of deep learning algorithms has enabled the generation of synthetic audio through Text-to-Speech (TTS) and Voice Conversion (VC) systems, exposing ASV systems to potential vulnerabilities. To counteract this, we propose a novel architecture named AASIST3. By enhancing the existing AASIST framework with Kolmogorov-Arnold networks, additional layers, encoders, and pre-emphasis techniques, AASIST3 achieves a more than twofold improvement in performance. It demonstrates minDCF results of 0.5357 in the closed condition and 0.1414 in the open condition, significantly enhancing the detection of synthetic voices and improving ASV security.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.17352v1</guid>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Kirill Borodin, Vasiliy Kudryavtsev, Dmitrii Korzh, Alexey Efimenko, Grach Mkrtchian, Mikhail Gorodnichev, Oleg Y. Rogov</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Forget to Flourish: Leveraging Machine-Unlearning on Pretrained Language Models for Privacy Leakage</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.17354</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.17354v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Fine-tuning large language models on private data for downstream applications poses significant privacy risks in potentially exposing sensitive information. Several popular community platforms now offer convenient distribution of a large variety of pre-trained models, allowing anyone to publish without rigorous verification. This scenario creates a privacy threat, as pre-trained models can be intentionally crafted to compromise the privacy of fine-tuning datasets. In this study, we introduce a novel poisoning technique that uses model-unlearning as an attack tool. This approach manipulates a pre-trained language model to increase the leakage of private data during the fine-tuning process. Our method enhances both membership inference and data extraction attacks while preserving model utility. Experimental results across different models, datasets, and fine-tuning setups demonstrate that our attacks significantly surpass baseline performance. This work serves as a cautionary note for users who download pre-trained models from unverified sources, highlighting the potential risks involved.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.17354v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Md Rafi Ur Rashid, Jing Liu, Toshiaki Koike-Akino, Shagufta Mehnaz, Ye Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bidirectional Decoding: Improving Action Chunking via Closed-Loop Resampling</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.17355</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.17355v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Predicting and executing a sequence of actions without intermediate replanning, known as action chunking, is increasingly used in robot learning from human demonstrations. However, its effects on learned policies remain puzzling: some studies highlight its importance for achieving strong performance, while others observe detrimental effects. In this paper, we first dissect the role of action chunking by analyzing the divergence between the learner and the demonstrator. We find that longer action chunks enable a policy to better capture temporal dependencies by taking into account more past states and actions within the chunk. However, this advantage comes at the cost of exacerbating errors in stochastic environments due to fewer observations of recent states. To address this, we propose Bidirectional Decoding (BID), a test-time inference algorithm that bridges action chunking with closed-loop operations. BID samples multiple predictions at each time step and searches for the optimal one based on two criteria: (i) backward coherence, which favors samples aligned with previous decisions, (ii) forward contrast, which favors samples close to outputs of a stronger policy and distant from those of a weaker policy. By coupling decisions within and across action chunks, BID enhances temporal consistency over extended sequences while enabling adaptive replanning in stochastic environments. Experimental results show that BID substantially outperforms conventional closed-loop operations of two state-of-the-art generative policies across seven simulation benchmarks and two real-world tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.17355v1</guid>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yuejiang Liu, Jubayer Ibn Hamid, Annie Xie, Yoonho Lee, Maximilian Du, Chelsea Finn</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>C-RADAR: A Centralized Deep Learning System for Intrusion Detection in Software Defined Networks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.17356</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.17356v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: The popularity of Software Defined Networks (SDNs) has grown in recent years, mainly because of their ability to simplify network management and improve network flexibility. However, this also makes them vulnerable to various types of cyber attacks. SDNs work on a centralized control plane which makes them more prone to network attacks. Research has demonstrated that deep learning (DL) methods can be successful in identifying intrusions in conventional networks, but their application in SDNs is still an open research area. In this research, we propose the use of DL techniques for intrusion detection in SDNs. We measure the effectiveness of our method by experimentation on a dataset of network traffic and comparing it to existing techniques. Our results show that the DL-based approach outperforms traditional methods in terms of detection accuracy and computational efficiency. The deep learning architecture that has been used in this research is a Long Short Term Memory Network and Self-Attention based architecture i.e. LSTM-Attn which achieves an Fl-score of 0.9721. Furthermore, this technique can be trained to detect new attack patterns and improve the overall security of SDNs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.17356v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1109/C-CODE58145.2023.10139892</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Osama Mustafa, Khizer Ali, Talha Naqash</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leveraging Graph Neural Networks to Forecast Electricity Consumption</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.17366</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.17366v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Accurate electricity demand forecasting is essential for several reasons, especially as the integration of renewable energy sources and the transition to a decentralized network paradigm introduce greater complexity and uncertainty. The proposed methodology leverages graph-based representations to effectively capture the spatial distribution and relational intricacies inherent in this decentralized network structure. This research work offers a novel approach that extends beyond the conventional Generalized Additive Model framework by considering models like Graph Convolutional Networks or Graph SAGE. These graph-based models enable the incorporation of various levels of interconnectedness and information sharing among nodes, where each node corresponds to the combined load (i.e. consumption) of a subset of consumers (e.g. the regions of a country). More specifically, we introduce a range of methods for inferring graphs tailored to consumption forecasting, along with a framework for evaluating the developed models in terms of both performance and explainability. We conduct experiments on electricity forecasting, in both a synthetic and a real framework considering the French mainland regions, and the performance and merits of our approach are discussed.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.17366v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Eloi Campagne, Yvenn Amara-Ouali, Yannig Goude, Argyris Kalogeratos</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NDP: Next Distribution Prediction as a More Broad Target</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.17377</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.17377v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) trained on next-token prediction (NTP) paradigm have demonstrated powerful capabilities. However, the existing NTP paradigm contains several limitations, particularly related to planned task complications and error propagation during inference. In our work, we extend the critique of NTP, highlighting its limitation also due to training with a narrow objective: the prediction of a sub-optimal one-hot distribution. To support this critique, we conducted a pre-experiment treating the output distribution from powerful LLMs as efficient world data compression. By evaluating the similarity between the $n$-gram distribution and the one-hot distribution with LLMs, we observed that the $n$-gram distributions align more closely with the output distribution of LLMs. Based on this insight, we introduce Next Distribution Prediction (NDP), which uses $n$-gram distributions to replace the one-hot targets, enhancing learning without extra online training time. We conducted experiments across translation, general task, language transfer, and medical domain adaptation. Compared to NTP, NDP can achieve up to +2.97 COMET improvement in translation tasks, +0.61 average improvement in general tasks, and incredible +10.75 average improvement in the medical domain. This demonstrates the concrete benefits of addressing the target narrowing problem, pointing to a new direction for future work on improving NTP.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.17377v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Junhao Ruan, Abudukeyumu Abudula, Xinyu Liu, Bei Li, Yinqiao Li, Chenglong Wang, Yuchun Fan, Yuan Ge, Tong Xiao, Jingbo Zhu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EMPOWER: Embodied Multi-role Open-vocabulary Planning with Online Grounding and Execution</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.17379</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.17379v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Task planning for robots in real-life settings presents significant challenges. These challenges stem from three primary issues: the difficulty in identifying grounded sequences of steps to achieve a goal; the lack of a standardized mapping between high-level actions and low-level commands; and the challenge of maintaining low computational overhead given the limited resources of robotic hardware. We introduce EMPOWER, a framework designed for open-vocabulary online grounding and planning for embodied agents aimed at addressing these issues. By leveraging efficient pre-trained foundation models and a multi-role mechanism, EMPOWER demonstrates notable improvements in grounded planning and execution. Quantitative results highlight the effectiveness of our approach, achieving an average success rate of 0.73 across six different real-life scenarios using a TIAGo robot.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.17379v1</guid>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Francesco Argenziano, Michele Brienza, Vincenzo Suriani, Daniele Nardi, Domenico D. Bloisi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MoRe Fine-Tuning with 10x Fewer Parameters</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.17383</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.17383v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Parameter-efficient fine-tuning (PEFT) techniques have unlocked the potential to cheaply and easily specialize large pretrained models. However, the most prominent approaches, like low-rank adapters (LoRA), depend on heuristics or rules-of-thumb for their architectural choices -- potentially limiting their performance for new models and architectures. This limitation suggests that techniques from neural architecture search could be used to obtain optimal adapter architectures, but these are often expensive and difficult to implement. We address this challenge with Monarch Rectangular Fine-tuning (MoRe), a simple framework to search over adapter architectures that relies on the Monarch matrix class. Theoretically, we show that MoRe is more expressive than LoRA. Empirically, our approach is more parameter-efficient and performant than state-of-the-art PEFTs on a range of tasks and models, with as few as 5\% of LoRA's parameters.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.17383v1</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Wenxuan Tan, Nicholas Roberts, Tzu-Heng Huang, Jitian Zhao, John Cooper, Samuel Guo, Chengyu Duan, Frederic Sala</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting Inspiration for Feature Elicitation: App Store- vs. LLM-based Approach</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.17404</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.17404v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Over the past decade, app store (AppStore)-inspired requirements elicitation has proven to be highly beneficial. Developers often explore competitors' apps to gather inspiration for new features. With the advance of Generative AI, recent studies have demonstrated the potential of large language model (LLM)-inspired requirements elicitation. LLMs can assist in this process by providing inspiration for new feature ideas. While both approaches are gaining popularity in practice, there is a lack of insight into their differences. We report on a comparative study between AppStore- and LLM-based approaches for refining features into sub-features. By manually analyzing 1,200 sub-features recommended from both approaches, we identified their benefits, challenges, and key differences. While both approaches recommend highly relevant sub-features with clear descriptions, LLMs seem more powerful particularly concerning novel unseen app scopes. Moreover, some recommended features are imaginary with unclear feasibility, which suggests the importance of a human-analyst in the elicitation loop.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.17404v1</guid>
      <category>cs.SE</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jialiang Wei, Anne-Lise Courbis, Thomas Lambolais, Binbin Xu, Pierre Louis Bernard, G\'erard Dray, Walid Maalej</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Open-vocabulary Temporal Action Localization using VLMs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.17422</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.17422v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Video action localization aims to find timings of a specific action from a long video. Although existing learning-based approaches have been successful, those require annotating videos that come with a considerable labor cost. This paper proposes a learning-free, open-vocabulary approach based on emerging vision-language models (VLM). The challenge stems from the fact that VLMs are neither designed to process long videos nor tailored for finding actions. We overcome these problems by extending an iterative visual prompting technique. Specifically, we sample video frames into a concatenated image with frame index labels, making a VLM guess a frame that is considered to be closest to the start/end of the action. Iterating this process by narrowing a sampling time window results in finding a specific frame of start and end of an action. We demonstrate that this sampling technique yields reasonable results, illustrating a practical extension of VLMs for understanding videos.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.17422v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Naoki Wake, Atsushi Kanehira, Kazuhiro Sasabuchi, Jun Takamatsu, Katsushi Ikeuchi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advancing Multi-talker ASR Performance with Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.17431</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.17431v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Recognizing overlapping speech from multiple speakers in conversational scenarios is one of the most challenging problem for automatic speech recognition (ASR). Serialized output training (SOT) is a classic method to address multi-talker ASR, with the idea of concatenating transcriptions from multiple speakers according to the emission times of their speech for training. However, SOT-style transcriptions, derived from concatenating multiple related utterances in a conversation, depend significantly on modeling long contexts. Therefore, compared to traditional methods that primarily emphasize encoder performance in attention-based encoder-decoder (AED) architectures, a novel approach utilizing large language models (LLMs) that leverages the capabilities of pre-trained decoders may be better suited for such complex and challenging scenarios. In this paper, we propose an LLM-based SOT approach for multi-talker ASR, leveraging pre-trained speech encoder and LLM, fine-tuning them on multi-talker dataset using appropriate strategies. Experimental results demonstrate that our approach surpasses traditional AED-based methods on the simulated dataset LibriMix and achieves state-of-the-art performance on the evaluation set of the real-world dataset AMI, outperforming the AED model trained with 1000 times more supervised data in previous works.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.17431v1</guid>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mohan Shi, Zengrui Jin, Yaoxun Xu, Yong Xu, Shi-Xiong Zhang, Kun Wei, Yiwen Shao, Chunlei Zhang, Dong Yu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bridging Episodes and Semantics: A Novel Framework for Long-Form Video Understanding</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.17443</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.17443v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: While existing research often treats long-form videos as extended short videos, we propose a novel approach that more accurately reflects human cognition. This paper introduces BREASE: BRidging Episodes And SEmantics for Long-Form Video Understanding, a model that simulates episodic memory accumulation to capture action sequences and reinforces them with semantic knowledge dispersed throughout the video. Our work makes two key contributions: First, we develop an Episodic COmpressor (ECO) that efficiently aggregates crucial representations from micro to semi-macro levels. Second, we propose a Semantics reTRiever (SeTR) that enhances these aggregated representations with semantic information by focusing on the broader context, dramatically reducing feature dimensionality while preserving relevant macro-level information. Extensive experiments demonstrate that BREASE achieves state-of-the-art performance across multiple long video understanding benchmarks in both zero-shot and fully-supervised settings. The project page and code are at: https://joslefaure.github.io/assets/html/hermes.html.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.17443v1</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Gueter Josmy Faure, Jia-Fong Yeh, Min-Hung Chen, Hung-Ting Su, Winston H. Hsu, Shang-Hong Lai</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Agent Collaboration through Heuristic Multi-Agent Planning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2301.01246</link>
      <description>arXiv:2301.01246v5 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The SOTA algorithms for addressing QDec-POMDP issues, QDec-FP and QDec-FPS, are unable to effectively tackle problems that involve different types of sensing agents. We propose a new algorithm that addresses this issue by requiring agents to adopt the same plan if one agent is unable to take a sensing action but the other can. Our algorithm performs significantly better than both QDec-FP and QDec-FPS in these types of situations.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2301.01246v5</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.MA</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Nitsan Soffair</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scale-Adaptive Balancing of Exploration and Exploitation in Classical Planning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2305.09840</link>
      <description>arXiv:2305.09840v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Balancing exploration and exploitation has been an important problem in both game tree search and automated planning. However, while the problem has been extensively analyzed within the Multi-Armed Bandit (MAB) literature, the planning community has had limited success when attempting to apply those results. We show that a more detailed theoretical understanding of MAB literature helps improve existing planning algorithms that are based on Monte Carlo Tree Search (MCTS) / Trial Based Heuristic Tree Search (THTS). In particular, THTS uses UCB1 MAB algorithms in an ad hoc manner, as UCB1's theoretical requirement of fixed bounded support reward distributions is not satisfied within heuristic search for classical planning. The core issue lies in UCB1's lack of adaptations to the different scales of the rewards. We propose GreedyUCT-Normal, a MCTS/THTS algorithm with UCB1-Normal bandit for agile classical planning, which handles distributions with different scales by taking the reward variance into consideration, and resulted in an improved algorithmic performance (more plans found with less node expansions) that outperforms Greedy Best First Search and existing MCTS/THTS-based algorithms (GreedyUCT,GreedyUCT*).</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2305.09840v3</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Stephen Wissow, Masataro Asai</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recording and Describing Poker Hands</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2312.11753</link>
      <description>arXiv:2312.11753v5 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: This paper introduces the Poker Hand History (PHH) file format, designed to standardize the recording of poker hands across different game variants. Despite poker's widespread popularity in the mainstream culture as a mind sport and its prominence in the field of artificial intelligence (AI) research as a benchmark for imperfect information AI agents, it lacks a consistent format that humans can use to document poker hands across different variants that can also easily be parsed by machines. To address this gap in the literature, we propose the PHH format which provides a concise human-readable machine-friendly representation of hand history that comprehensively captures various details of the hand, ranging from initial game parameters and actions to contextual parameters including but not limited to the venue, players, and time control information. In the supplementary, we provide 10,088 hands covering 11 different variants in the PHH format. The full specification is available on https://github.com/uoftcprg/phh-std</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2312.11753v5</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1109/CoG60054.2024.10645611</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>2024 IEEE Conference on Games (CoG), Milan, Italy, 2024, pp. 1-8.</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Juho Kim</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generative Design of Crystal Structures by Point Cloud Representations and Diffusion Model</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.13192</link>
      <description>arXiv:2401.13192v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Efficiently generating energetically stable crystal structures has long been a challenge in material design, primarily due to the immense arrangement of atoms in a crystal lattice. To facilitate the discovery of stable material, we present a framework for the generation of synthesizable materials, leveraging a point cloud representation to encode intricate structural information. At the heart of this framework lies the introduction of a diffusion model as its foundational pillar. To gauge the efficacy of our approach, we employ it to reconstruct input structures from our training datasets, rigorously validating its high reconstruction performance. Furthermore, we demonstrate the profound potential of Point Cloud-Based Crystal Diffusion (PCCD) by generating entirely new materials, emphasizing their synthesizability. Our research stands as a noteworthy contribution to the advancement of materials design and synthesis through the cutting-edge avenue of generative design instead of the conventional substitution or experience-based discovery.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2401.13192v3</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>physics.comp-ph</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhelin Li, Rami Mrad, Runxian Jiao, Guan Huang, Jun Shan, Shibing Chu, Yuanping Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advancing Chinese biomedical text mining with community challenges</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.04261</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.04261v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Objective: This study aims to review the recent advances in community challenges for biomedical text mining in China. Methods: We collected information of evaluation tasks released in community challenges of biomedical text mining, including task description, dataset description, data source, task type and related links. A systematic summary and comparative analysis were conducted on various biomedical natural language processing tasks, such as named entity recognition, entity normalization, attribute extraction, relation extraction, event extraction, text classification, text similarity, knowledge graph construction, question answering, text generation, and large language model evaluation. Results: We identified 39 evaluation tasks from 6 community challenges that spanned from 2017 to 2023. Our analysis revealed the diverse range of evaluation task types and data sources in biomedical text mining. We explored the potential clinical applications of these community challenge tasks from a translational biomedical informatics perspective. We compared with their English counterparts, and discussed the contributions, limitations, lessons and guidelines of these community challenges, while highlighting future directions in the era of large language models. Conclusion: Community challenge evaluation competitions have played a crucial role in promoting technology innovation and fostering interdisciplinary collaboration in the field of biomedical text mining. These challenges provide valuable platforms for researchers to develop state-of-the-art solutions.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.04261v2</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1016/j.jbi.2024.104716</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Journal of Biomedical Informatics. 2024;157:104716.</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Hui Zong, Rongrong Wu, Jiaxue Cha, Weizhe Feng, Erman Wu, Jiakun Li, Aibin Shao, Liang Tao, Zuofeng Li, Buzhou Tang, Bairong Shen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Use of a Structured Knowledge Base Enhances Metadata Curation by Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.05893</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.05893v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Metadata play a crucial role in ensuring the findability, accessibility, interoperability, and reusability of datasets. This paper investigates the potential of large language models (LLMs), specifically GPT-4, to improve adherence to metadata standards. We conducted experiments on 200 random data records describing human samples relating to lung cancer from the NCBI BioSample repository, evaluating GPT-4's ability to suggest edits for adherence to metadata standards. We computed the adherence accuracy of field name-field value pairs through a peer review process, and we observed a marginal average improvement in adherence to the standard data dictionary from 79% to 80% (p&lt;0.5). We then prompted GPT-4 with domain information in the form of the textual descriptions of CEDAR templates and recorded a significant improvement to 97% from 79% (p&lt;0.01). These results indicate that, while LLMs may not be able to correct legacy metadata to ensure satisfactory adherence to standards when unaided, they do show promise for use in automated metadata curation when integrated with a structured knowledge base</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.05893v4</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sowmya S. Sundaram, Benjamin Solomon, Avani Khatri, Anisha Laumas, Purvesh Khatri, Mark A. Musen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimal and Bounded Suboptimal Any-Angle Multi-agent Pathfinding</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.16379</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.16379v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Multi-agent pathfinding (MAPF) is the problem of finding a set of conflict-free paths for a set of agents. Typically, the agents' moves are limited to a pre-defined graph of possible locations and allowed transitions between them, e.g. a 4-neighborhood grid. We explore how to solve MAPF problems when each agent can move between any pair of possible locations as long as traversing the line segment connecting them does not lead to a collision with the obstacles. This is known as any-angle pathfinding. We present the first optimal any-angle multi-agent pathfinding algorithm. Our planner is based on the Continuous Conflict-based Search (CCBS) algorithm and an optimal any-angle variant of the Safe Interval Path Planning (TO-AA-SIPP). The straightforward combination of those, however, scales poorly since any-angle path finding induces search trees with a very large branching factor. To mitigate this, we adapt two techniques from classical MAPF to the any-angle setting, namely Disjoint Splitting and Multi-Constraints. Experimental results on different combinations of these techniques show they enable solving over 30% more problems than the vanilla combination of CCBS and TO-AA-SIPP. In addition, we present a bounded-suboptimal variant of our algorithm, that enables trading runtime for solution cost in a controlled manner.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.16379v2</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.MA</category>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Konstantin Yakovlev, Anton Andreychuk, Roni Stern</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Isopignistic Canonical Decomposition via Belief Evolution Network</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.02653</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.02653v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Developing a general information processing model in uncertain environments is fundamental for the advancement of explainable artificial intelligence. Dempster-Shafer theory of evidence is a well-known and effective reasoning method for representing epistemic uncertainty, which is closely related to subjective probability theory and possibility theory. Although they can be transformed to each other under some particular belief structures, there remains a lack of a clear and interpretable transformation process, as well as a unified approach for information processing. In this paper, we aim to address these issues from the perspectives of isopignistic belief functions and the hyper-cautious transferable belief model. Firstly, we propose an isopignistic transformation based on the belief evolution network. This transformation allows for the adjustment of the information granule while retaining the potential decision outcome. The isopignistic transformation is integrated with a hyper-cautious transferable belief model to establish a new canonical decomposition. This decomposition offers a reverse path between the possibility distribution and its isopignistic mass functions. The result of the canonical decomposition, called isopignistic function, is an identical information content distribution to reflect the propensity and relative commitment degree of the BPA. Furthermore, this paper introduces a method to reconstruct the basic belief assignment by adjusting the isopignistic function. It explores the advantages of this approach in modeling and handling uncertainty within the hyper-cautious transferable belief model. More general, this paper establishes a theoretical basis for building general models of artificial intelligence based on probability theory, Dempster-Shafer theory, and possibility theory.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.02653v2</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Qianli Zhou, Tianxiang Zhan, Yong Deng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI in Space for Scientific Missions: Strategies for Minimizing Neural-Network Model Upload</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.14297</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.14297v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Artificial Intelligence (AI) has the potential to revolutionize space exploration by delegating several spacecraft decisions to an onboard AI instead of relying on ground control and predefined procedures. It is likely that there will be an AI/ML Processing Unit onboard the spacecraft running an inference engine. The neural-network will have pre-installed parameters that can be updated onboard by uploading, by telecommands, parameters obtained by training on the ground. However, satellite uplinks have limited bandwidth and transmissions can be costly. Furthermore, a mission operating with a suboptimal neural network will miss out on valuable scientific data. Smaller networks can thereby decrease the uplink cost, while increasing the value of the scientific data that is downloaded. In this work, we evaluate and discuss the use of reduced-precision and bare-minimum neural networks to reduce the time for upload. As an example of an AI use case, we focus on the NASA's Magnetosperic MultiScale (MMS) mission. We show how an AI onboard could be used in the Earth's magnetosphere to classify data to selectively downlink higher value data or to recognize a region-of-interest to trigger a burst-mode, collecting data at a high-rate. Using a simple filtering scheme and algorithm, we show how the start and end of a region-of-interest can be detected in on a stream of classifications. To provide the classifications, we use an established Convolutional Neural Network (CNN) trained to an accuracy &gt;94%. We also show how the network can be reduced to a single linear layer and trained to the same accuracy as the established CNN. Thereby, reducing the overall size of the model by up to 98.9%. We further show how each network can be reduced by up to 75% of its original size, by using lower-precision formats to represent the network parameters, with a change in accuracy of less than 0.6 percentage points.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.14297v2</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>astro-ph.IM</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jonah Ekelund, Ricardo Vinuesa, Yuri Khotyaintsev, Pierre Henri, Gian Luca Delzanno, Stefano Markidis</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PEER: Expertizing Domain-Specific Tasks with a Multi-Agent Framework and Tuning Methods</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.06985</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.06985v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In domain-specific applications, GPT-4, augmented with precise prompts or Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG), shows notable potential but faces the critical tri-lemma of performance, cost, and data privacy. High performance requires sophisticated processing techniques, yet managing multiple agents within a complex workflow often proves costly and challenging. To address this, we introduce the PEER (Plan, Execute, Express, Review) multi-agent framework. This systematizes domain-specific tasks by integrating precise question decomposition, advanced information retrieval, comprehensive summarization, and rigorous self-assessment. Given the concerns of cost and data privacy, enterprises are shifting from proprietary models like GPT-4 to custom models, striking a balance between cost, security, and performance. We developed industrial practices leveraging online data and user feedback for efficient model tuning. This study provides best practice guidelines for applying multi-agent systems in domain-specific problem-solving and implementing effective agent tuning strategies. Our empirical studies, particularly in the financial question-answering domain, demonstrate that our approach achieves 95.0% of GPT-4's performance, while effectively managing costs and ensuring data privacy.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.06985v4</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yiying Wang, Xiaojing Li, Binzhu Wang, Yueyang Zhou, Yingru Lin, Han Ji, Hong Chen, Jinshi Zhang, Fei Yu, Zewei Zhao, Song Jin, Renji Gong, Wanqing Xu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A mathematical framework of intelligence and consciousness based on Riemannian Geometry</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.11024</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.11024v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Understanding intelligence is a central pursuit in neuroscience, cognitive science, and artificial intelligence. Intelligence encompasses learning, problem-solving, creativity, and even consciousness. Recent advancements in geometric analysis have revealed new insights into high-dimensional information representation and organisation, exposing intrinsic data structures and dynamic processes within neural and artificial systems. However, a comprehensive framework that unifies the static and dynamic aspects of intelligence is still lacking. This manuscript proposes a mathematical framework based on Riemannian geometry to describe the structure and dynamics of intelligence and consciousness. Intelligence elements are conceptualised as tokens embedded in a high-dimensional space. The learned token embeddings capture the interconnections of tokens across various scenarios and tasks, forming manifolds in the intelligence space. Thought flow is depicted as the sequential activation of tokens along geodesics within these manifolds. During the navigation of geodesics, consciousness, as a self-referential process, perceives the thought flow, evaluates it against predictions, and provides feedback through prediction errors, adjusting the geodesic: non-zero prediction errors, such as learning, lead to the restructuring of the curved manifolds, thus changing the geodesic of thought flow. This dynamic interaction integrates new information, evolves the geometry and facilitates learning. The geometry of intelligence guides consciousness, and consciousness structures the geometry of intelligence. By integrating geometric concepts, this proposed theory offers a unified, mathematically framework for describing the structure and dynamics of intelligence and consciousness. Applicable to biological and artificial intelligence, this framework may pave the way for future research and empirical validation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.11024v3</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>math.DG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Meng Lu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evolving Virtual World with Delta-Engine</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.05842</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.05842v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In this paper, we focus on the \emph{virtual world}, a cyberspace where people can live in. An ideal virtual world shares great similarity with our real world. One of the crucial aspects is its evolving nature, reflected by individuals' capability to grow and thereby influence the objective world. Such dynamics is unpredictable and beyond the reach of existing systems. For this, we propose a special engine called \textbf{\emph{Delta-Engine}} to drive this virtual world. $\Delta$ associates the world's evolution to the engine's scalability. It consists of a base engine and a neural proxy. The base engine programs the prototype of the virtual world; given a trigger, the neural proxy generates new snippets on the base engine through \emph{incremental prediction}. This paper presents a full-stack introduction to the delta-engine. The key feature of the delta-engine is its scalability to unknown elements within the world, Technically, it derives from the prefect co-work of the neural proxy and the base engine, and the alignment with high-quality data. We introduce an engine-oriented fine-tuning method that embeds the base engine into the proxy. We then discuss the human-LLM collaborative design to produce novel and interesting data efficiently. Eventually, we propose three evaluation principles to comprehensively assess the performance of a delta engine: naive evaluation, incremental evaluation, and adversarial evaluation.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.05842v3</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hongqiu Wu, Zekai Xu, Tianyang Xu, Shize Wei, Yan Wang, Jiale Hong, Weiqi Wu, Hai Zhao, Min Zhang, Zhezhi He</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Perceptual Similarity for Measuring Decision-Making Style and Policy Diversity in Games</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.06051</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.06051v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Defining and measuring decision-making styles, also known as playstyles, is crucial in gaming, where these styles reflect a broad spectrum of individuality and diversity. However, finding a universally applicable measure for these styles poses a challenge. Building on Playstyle Distance, the first unsupervised metric to measure playstyle similarity based on game screens and raw actions, we introduce three enhancements to increase accuracy: multiscale analysis with varied state granularity, a perceptual kernel rooted in psychology, and the utilization of the intersection-over-union method for efficient evaluation. These innovations not only advance measurement precision but also offer insights into human cognition of similarity. Across two racing games and seven Atari games, our techniques significantly improve the precision of zero-shot playstyle classification, achieving an accuracy exceeding 90 percent with fewer than 512 observation-action pairs, which is less than half an episode of these games. Furthermore, our experiments with 2048 and Go demonstrate the potential of discrete playstyle measures in puzzle and board games. We also develop an algorithm for assessing decision-making diversity using these measures. Our findings improve the measurement of end-to-end game analysis and the evolution of artificial intelligence for diverse playstyles.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.06051v2</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.IR</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Chiu-Chou Lin, Wei-Chen Chiu, I-Chen Wu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Differentiable Edge-based OPC</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.08969</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.08969v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Optical proximity correction (OPC) is crucial for pushing the boundaries of semiconductor manufacturing and enabling the continued scaling of integrated circuits. While pixel-based OPC, termed as inverse lithography technology (ILT), has gained research interest due to its flexibility and precision. Its complexity and intricate features can lead to challenges in mask writing, increased defects, and higher costs, hence hindering widespread industrial adoption. In this paper, we propose DiffOPC, a differentiable OPC framework that enjoys the virtue of both edge-based OPC and ILT. By employing a mask rule-aware gradient-based optimization approach, DiffOPC efficiently guides mask edge segment movement during mask optimization, minimizing wafer error by propagating true gradients from the cost function back to the mask edges. Our approach achieves lower edge placement error while reducing manufacturing cost by half compared to state-of-the-art OPC techniques, bridging the gap between the high accuracy of pixel-based OPC and the practicality required for industrial adoption, thus offering a promising solution for advanced semiconductor manufacturing.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.08969v3</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>physics.optics</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Guojin Chen, Haoyu Yang, Haoxing Ren, Bei Yu, David Z. Pan</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Minor DPO reject penalty to increase training robustness</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.09834</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.09834v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Learning from human preference is a paradigm used in large-scale language model (LLM) fine-tuning step to better align pretrained LLM to human preference for downstream task. In the past it uses reinforcement learning from human feedback (RLHF) algorithm to optimize the LLM policy to align with these preferences and not to draft too far from the original model. Recently, Direct Preference Optimization (DPO) has been proposed to solve the alignment problem with a simplified RL-free method. Using preference pairs of chosen and reject data, DPO models the relative log probability as implicit reward function and optimize LLM policy using a simple binary cross entropy objective directly. DPO is quite straight forward and easy to be understood. It perform efficiently and well in most cases. In this article, we analyze the working mechanism of $\beta$ in DPO, disclose its syntax difference between RL algorithm and DPO, and understand the potential shortage brought by the DPO simplification. With these insights, we propose MinorDPO, which is better aligned to the original RL algorithm, and increase the stability of preference optimization process.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.09834v3</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Shiming Xie, Hong Chen, Fred Yu, Zeye Sun, Xiuyu Wu, Yingfan Hu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Demystifying Reinforcement Learning in Production Scheduling via Explainable AI</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.09841</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.09841v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Deep Reinforcement Learning (DRL) is a frequently employed technique to solve scheduling problems. Although DRL agents ace at delivering viable results in short computing times, their reasoning remains opaque. We conduct a case study where we systematically apply two explainable AI (xAI) frameworks, namely SHAP (DeepSHAP) and Captum (Input x Gradient), to describe the reasoning behind scheduling decisions of a specialized DRL agent in a flow production. We find that methods in the xAI literature lack falsifiability and consistent terminology, do not adequately consider domain-knowledge, the target audience or real-world scenarios, and typically provide simple input-output explanations rather than causal interpretations. To resolve this issue, we introduce a hypotheses-based workflow. This approach enables us to inspect whether explanations align with domain knowledge and match the reward hypotheses of the agent. We furthermore tackle the challenge of communicating these insights to third parties by tailoring hypotheses to the target audience, which can serve as interpretations of the agent's behavior after verification. Our proposed workflow emphasizes the repeated verification of explanations and may be applicable to various DRL-based scheduling use cases.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.09841v2</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Daniel Fischer, Hannah M. H\"usener, Felix Grumbach, Lukas Vollenkemper, Arthur M\"uller, Pascal Reusch</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mini-Omni: Language Models Can Hear, Talk While Thinking in Streaming</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.16725</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.16725v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Recent advances in language models have achieved significant progress. GPT-4o, as a new milestone, has enabled real-time conversations with humans, demonstrating near-human natural fluency. Such human-computer interaction necessitates models with the capability to perform reasoning directly with the audio modality and generate output in streaming. However, this remains beyond the reach of current academic models, as they typically depend on extra TTS systems for speech synthesis, resulting in undesirable latency. This paper introduces the Mini-Omni, an audio-based end-to-end conversational model, capable of real-time speech interaction. To achieve this capability, we propose a text-instructed speech generation method, along with batch-parallel strategies during inference to further boost the performance. Our method also helps to retain the original model's language capabilities with minimal degradation, enabling other works to establish real-time interaction capabilities. We call this training method "Any Model Can Talk". We also introduce the VoiceAssistant-400K dataset to fine-tune models optimized for speech output. To our best knowledge, Mini-Omni is the first fully end-to-end, open-source model for real-time speech interaction, offering valuable potential for future research.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.16725v2</guid>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.HC</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhifei Xie, Changqiao Wu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dense-Sparse Deep Convolutional Neural Networks Training for Image Denoising</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2107.04857</link>
      <description>arXiv:2107.04857v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Recently, deep learning methods such as the convolutional neural networks have gained prominence in the area of image denoising. This is owing to their proven ability to surpass state-of-the-art classical image denoising algorithms such as block-matching and 3D filtering algorithm. Deep denoising convolutional neural networks use many feed-forward convolution layers with added regularization methods of batch normalization and residual learning to speed up training and improve denoising performance significantly. However, this comes at the expense of a huge number of trainable parameters. In this paper, we show that by employing an enhanced dense-sparse-dense network training procedure to the deep denoising convolutional neural networks, comparable denoising performance level can be achieved at a significantly reduced number of trainable parameters. We derive motivation from the fact that networks trained using the dense-sparse-dense approach have been shown to attain performance boost with reduced number of parameters. The proposed reduced deep denoising convolutional neural networks network is an efficient denoising model with significantly reduced parameters and comparable performance to the deep denoising convolutional neural networks. Additionally, denoising was achieved at significantly reduced processing time.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2107.04857v2</guid>
      <category>eess.IV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Basit O. Alawode, Mudassir Masood</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Does CLIP Bind Concepts? Probing Compositionality in Large Image Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2212.10537</link>
      <description>arXiv:2212.10537v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Large-scale neural network models combining text and images have made incredible progress in recent years. However, it remains an open question to what extent such models encode compositional representations of the concepts over which they operate, such as correctly identifying "red cube" by reasoning over the constituents "red" and "cube". In this work, we focus on the ability of a large pretrained vision and language model (CLIP) to encode compositional concepts and to bind variables in a structure-sensitive way (e.g., differentiating "cube behind sphere" from "sphere behind cube"). To inspect the performance of CLIP, we compare several architectures from research on compositional distributional semantics models (CDSMs), a line of research that attempts to implement traditional compositional linguistic structures within embedding spaces. We benchmark them on three synthetic datasets - single-object, two-object, and relational - designed to test concept binding. We find that CLIP can compose concepts in a single-object setting, but in situations where concept binding is needed, performance drops dramatically. At the same time, CDSMs also perform poorly, with best performance at chance level.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2212.10537v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>In Findings of the Association for Computational Linguistics, EACL 2024, pages 1487 - 1500, Malta. Association for Computational Linguistics</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Martha Lewis, Nihal V. Nayak, Peilin Yu, Qinan Yu, Jack Merullo, Stephen H. Bach, Ellie Pavlick</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scalable Multi-Agent Reinforcement Learning for Warehouse Logistics with Robotic and Human Co-Workers</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2212.11498</link>
      <description>arXiv:2212.11498v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: We consider a warehouse in which dozens of mobile robots and human pickers work together to collect and deliver items within the warehouse. The fundamental problem we tackle, called the order-picking problem, is how these worker agents must coordinate their movement and actions in the warehouse to maximise performance in this task. Established industry methods using heuristic approaches require large engineering efforts to optimise for innately variable warehouse configurations. In contrast, multi-agent reinforcement learning (MARL) can be flexibly applied to diverse warehouse configurations (e.g. size, layout, number/types of workers, item replenishment frequency), and different types of order-picking paradigms (e.g. Goods-to-Person and Person-to-Goods), as the agents can learn how to cooperate optimally through experience. We develop hierarchical MARL algorithms in which a manager agent assigns goals to worker agents, and the policies of the manager and workers are co-trained toward maximising a global objective (e.g. pick rate). Our hierarchical algorithms achieve significant gains in sample efficiency over baseline MARL algorithms and overall pick rates over multiple established industry heuristics in a diverse set of warehouse configurations and different order-picking paradigms.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2212.11498v3</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.MA</category>
      <category>cs.RO</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Aleksandar Krnjaic, Raul D. Steleac, Jonathan D. Thomas, Georgios Papoudakis, Lukas Sch\"afer, Andrew Wing Keung To, Kuan-Ho Lao, Murat Cubuktepe, Matthew Haley, Peter B\"orsting, Stefano V. Albrecht</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Incorporating Unlabelled Data into Bayesian Neural Networks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2304.01762</link>
      <description>arXiv:2304.01762v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Conventional Bayesian Neural Networks (BNNs) are unable to leverage unlabelled data to improve their predictions. To overcome this limitation, we introduce Self-Supervised Bayesian Neural Networks, which use unlabelled data to learn models with suitable prior predictive distributions. This is achieved by leveraging contrastive pretraining techniques and optimising a variational lower bound. We then show that the prior predictive distributions of self-supervised BNNs capture problem semantics better than conventional BNN priors. In turn, our approach offers improved predictive performance over conventional BNNs, especially in low-budget regimes.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2304.01762v3</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>stat.ML</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mrinank Sharma, Tom Rainforth, Yee Whye Teh, Vincent Fortuin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DiffLoad: Uncertainty Quantification in Electrical Load Forecasting with Diffusion Model</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2306.01001</link>
      <description>arXiv:2306.01001v4 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Electrical load forecasting plays a crucial role in decision-making for power systems, including unit commitment and economic dispatch. The integration of renewable energy sources and the occurrence of external events, such as the COVID-19 pandemic, have rapidly increased uncertainties in load forecasting. The uncertainties in load forecasting can be divided into two types: epistemic uncertainty and aleatoric uncertainty. Separating these types of uncertainties can help decision-makers better understand where and to what extent the uncertainty is, thereby enhancing their confidence in the following decision-making. This paper proposes a diffusion-based Seq2Seq structure to estimate epistemic uncertainty and employs the robust additive Cauchy distribution to estimate aleatoric uncertainty. Our method not only ensures the accuracy of load forecasting but also demonstrates the ability to separate the two types of uncertainties and be applicable to different levels of loads. The relevant code can be found at \url{https://anonymous.4open.science/r/DiffLoad-4714/}.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2306.01001v4</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>stat.ML</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhixian Wang, Qingsong Wen, Chaoli Zhang, Liang Sun, Yi Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diversifying the Mixture-of-Experts Representation for Language Models with Orthogonal Optimizer</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2310.09762</link>
      <description>arXiv:2310.09762v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: The Mixture of Experts (MoE) has emerged as a highly successful technique in deep learning, based on the principle of divide-and-conquer to maximize model capacity without significant additional computational cost. Even in the era of large-scale language models (LLMs), MoE continues to play a crucial role, as some researchers have indicated that GPT-4 adopts the MoE structure to ensure diverse inference results. However, MoE is susceptible to performance degeneracy, particularly evident in the issues of imbalance and homogeneous representation among experts. While previous studies have extensively addressed the problem of imbalance, the challenge of homogeneous representation remains unresolved. In this study, we shed light on the homogeneous representation problem, wherein experts in the MoE fail to specialize and lack diversity, leading to frustratingly high similarities in their representations (up to 99\% in a well-performed MoE model). This problem restricts the expressive power of the MoE and, we argue, contradicts its original intention. To tackle this issue, we propose a straightforward yet highly effective solution: OMoE, an orthogonal expert optimizer. Additionally, we introduce an alternating training strategy that encourages each expert to update in a direction orthogonal to the subspace spanned by other experts. Our algorithm facilitates MoE training in two key ways: firstly, it explicitly enhances representation diversity, and secondly, it implicitly fosters interaction between experts during orthogonal weights computation. Through extensive experiments, we demonstrate that our proposed optimization algorithm significantly improves the performance of fine-tuning the MoE model on the GLUE benchmark, SuperGLUE benchmark, question-answering task, and name entity recognition tasks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2310.09762v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Boan Liu, Liang Ding, Li Shen, Keqin Peng, Yu Cao, Dazhao Cheng, Dacheng Tao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring Adversarial Attacks on Deep Neural Networks for Targeted Class Manipulation Using DeepFool Algorithm</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2310.13019</link>
      <description>arXiv:2310.13019v4 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: The susceptibility of deep neural networks (DNNs) to adversarial attacks undermines their reliability across numerous applications, underscoring the necessity for an in-depth exploration of these vulnerabilities and the formulation of robust defense strategies. The DeepFool algorithm by Moosavi-Dezfooli et al. (2016) represents a pivotal step in identifying minimal perturbations required to induce misclassification of input images. Nonetheless, its generic methodology falls short in scenarios necessitating targeted interventions. Additionally, previous research studies have predominantly concentrated on the success rate of attacks without adequately addressing the consequential distortion of images, the maintenance of image quality, or the confidence threshold required for misclassification. To bridge these gaps, we introduce the Enhanced Targeted DeepFool (ET DeepFool) algorithm, an evolution of DeepFool that not only facilitates the specification of desired misclassification targets but also incorporates a configurable minimum confidence score. Our empirical investigations demonstrate the superiority of this refined approach in maintaining the integrity of images and minimizing perturbations across a variety of DNN architectures. Unlike previous iterations, such as the Targeted DeepFool by Gajjar et al. (2022), our method grants unparalleled control over the perturbation process, enabling precise manipulation of model responses. Preliminary outcomes reveal that certain models, including AlexNet and the advanced Vision Transformer, display commendable robustness to such manipulations. This discovery of varying levels of model robustness, as unveiled through our confidence level adjustments, could have far-reaching implications for the field of image recognition. Our code will be made public upon acceptance of the paper.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2310.13019v4</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>S. M. Fazle Rabby Labib, Joyanta Jyoti Mondal, Meem Arafat Manab, Sarfaraz Newaz, Xi Xiao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Survey on Knowledge Editing of Neural Networks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2310.19704</link>
      <description>arXiv:2310.19704v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Deep neural networks are becoming increasingly pervasive in academia and industry, matching and surpassing human performance on a wide variety of fields and related tasks. However, just as humans, even the largest artificial neural networks make mistakes, and once-correct predictions can become invalid as the world progresses in time. Augmenting datasets with samples that account for mistakes or up-to-date information has become a common workaround in practical applications. However, the well-known phenomenon of catastrophic forgetting poses a challenge in achieving precise changes in the implicitly memorized knowledge of neural network parameters, often requiring a full model re-training to achieve desired behaviors. That is expensive, unreliable, and incompatible with the current trend of large self-supervised pre-training, making it necessary to find more efficient and effective methods for adapting neural network models to changing data. To address this need, knowledge editing is emerging as a novel area of research that aims to enable reliable, data-efficient, and fast changes to a pre-trained target model, without affecting model behaviors on previously learned tasks. In this survey, we provide a brief review of this recent artificial intelligence field of research. We first introduce the problem of editing neural networks, formalize it in a common framework and differentiate it from more notorious branches of research such as continuous learning. Next, we provide a review of the most relevant knowledge editing approaches and datasets proposed so far, grouping works under four different families: regularization techniques, meta-learning, direct model editing, and architectural strategies. Finally, we outline some intersections with other fields of research and potential directions for future works.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2310.19704v3</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Vittorio Mazzia, Alessandro Pedrani, Andrea Caciolai, Kay Rottmann, Davide Bernardi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effectiveness of probabilistic contact tracing in epidemic containment: the role of super-spreaders and transmission path reconstruction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2312.00910</link>
      <description>arXiv:2312.00910v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: The recent COVID-19 pandemic underscores the significance of early-stage non-pharmacological intervention strategies. The widespread use of masks and the systematic implementation of contact tracing strategies provide a potentially equally effective and socially less impactful alternative to more conventional approaches, such as large-scale mobility restrictions. However, manual contact tracing faces strong limitations in accessing the network of contacts, and the scalability of currently implemented protocols for smartphone-based digital contact tracing becomes impractical during the rapid expansion phases of the outbreaks, due to the surge in exposure notifications and associated tests. A substantial improvement in digital contact tracing can be obtained through the integration of probabilistic techniques for risk assessment that can more effectively guide the allocation of new diagnostic tests. In this study, we first quantitatively analyze the diagnostic and social costs associated with these containment measures based on contact tracing, employing three state-of-the-art models of SARS-CoV-2 spreading. Our results suggest that probabilistic techniques allow for more effective mitigation at a lower cost. Secondly, our findings reveal a remarkable efficacy of probabilistic contact-tracing techniques in performing backward and multi-step tracing and capturing super-spreading events.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2312.00910v2</guid>
      <category>q-bio.PE</category>
      <category>cond-mat.stat-mech</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>physics.soc-ph</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1093/pnasnexus/pgae377</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>A. P. Muntoni, F. Mazza, A. Braunstein, G. Catania, L. Dall'Asta</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Language models align with human judgments on key grammatical constructions</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.01676</link>
      <description>arXiv:2402.01676v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Do large language models (LLMs) make human-like linguistic generalizations? Dentella et al. (2023) ("DGL") prompt several LLMs ("Is the following sentence grammatically correct in English?") to elicit grammaticality judgments of 80 English sentences, concluding that LLMs demonstrate a "yes-response bias" and a "failure to distinguish grammatical from ungrammatical sentences". We re-evaluate LLM performance using well-established practices and find that DGL's data in fact provide evidence for just how well LLMs capture human behaviors. Models not only achieve high accuracy overall, but also capture fine-grained variation in human linguistic judgments.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2402.01676v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1073/pnas.2400917121</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, 121(36), e2400917121 (2024)</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Jennifer Hu, Kyle Mahowald, Gary Lupyan, Anna Ivanova, Roger Levy</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AgentsCourt: Building Judicial Decision-Making Agents with Court Debate Simulation and Legal Knowledge Augmentation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.02959</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.02959v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: With the development of deep learning, natural language processing technology has effectively improved the efficiency of various aspects of the traditional judicial industry. However, most current efforts focus on tasks within individual judicial stages, making it difficult to handle complex tasks that span multiple stages. As the autonomous agents powered by large language models are becoming increasingly smart and able to make complex decisions in real-world settings, offering new insights for judicial intelligence. In this paper, (1) we propose a novel multi-agent framework, AgentsCourt, for judicial decision-making. Our framework follows the classic court trial process, consisting of court debate simulation, legal resources retrieval and decision-making refinement to simulate the decision-making of judge. (2) we introduce SimuCourt, a judicial benchmark that encompasses 420 Chinese judgment documents, spanning the three most common types of judicial cases. Furthermore, to support this task, we construct a large-scale legal knowledge base, Legal-KB, with multi-resource legal knowledge. (3) Extensive experiments show that our framework outperforms the existing advanced methods in various aspects, especially in generating legal articles, where our model achieves significant improvements of 8.6% and 9.1% F1 score in the first and second instance settings, respectively.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.02959v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Zhitao He, Pengfei Cao, Chenhao Wang, Zhuoran Jin, Yubo Chen, Jiexin Xu, Huaijun Li, Xiaojian Jiang, Kang Liu, Jun Zhao</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Large Language Multimodal Models for 5-Year Chronic Disease Cohort Prediction Using EHR Data</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.04785</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.04785v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Chronic diseases such as diabetes are the leading causes of morbidity and mortality worldwide. Numerous research studies have been attempted with various deep learning models in diagnosis. However, most previous studies had certain limitations, including using publicly available datasets (e.g. MIMIC), and imbalanced data. In this study, we collected five-year electronic health records (EHRs) from the Taiwan hospital database, including 1,420,596 clinical notes, 387,392 laboratory test results, and more than 1,505 laboratory test items, focusing on research pre-training large language models. We proposed a novel Large Language Multimodal Models (LLMMs) framework incorporating multimodal data from clinical notes and laboratory test results for the prediction of chronic disease risk. Our method combined a text embedding encoder and multi-head attention layer to learn laboratory test values, utilizing a deep neural network (DNN) module to merge blood features with chronic disease semantics into a latent space. In our experiments, we observe that clinicalBERT and PubMed-BERT, when combined with attention fusion, can achieve an accuracy of 73% in multiclass chronic diseases and diabetes prediction. By transforming laboratory test values into textual descriptions and employing the Flan T-5 model, we achieved a 76% Area Under the ROC Curve (AUROC), demonstrating the effectiveness of leveraging numerical text data for training and inference in language models. This approach significantly improves the accuracy of early-stage diabetes prediction.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.04785v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jun-En Ding, Phan Nguyen Minh Thao, Wen-Chih Peng, Jian-Zhe Wang, Chun-Cheng Chug, Min-Chen Hsieh, Yun-Chien Tseng, Ling Chen, Dongsheng Luo, Chi-Te Wang, Pei-fu Chen, Feng Liu, Fang-Ming Hung</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emergence of Social Norms in Generative Agent Societies: Principles and Architecture</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.08251</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.08251v4 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Social norms play a crucial role in guiding agents towards understanding and adhering to standards of behavior, thus reducing social conflicts within multi-agent systems (MASs). However, current LLM-based (or generative) MASs lack the capability to be normative. In this paper, we propose a novel architecture, named CRSEC, to empower the emergence of social norms within generative MASs. Our architecture consists of four modules: Creation &amp; Representation, Spreading, Evaluation, and Compliance. This addresses several important aspects of the emergent processes all in one: (i) where social norms come from, (ii) how they are formally represented, (iii) how they spread through agents' communications and observations, (iv) how they are examined with a sanity check and synthesized in the long term, and (v) how they are incorporated into agents' planning and actions. Our experiments deployed in the Smallville sandbox game environment demonstrate the capability of our architecture to establish social norms and reduce social conflicts within generative MASs. The positive outcomes of our human evaluation, conducted with 30 evaluators, further affirm the effectiveness of our approach. Our project can be accessed via the following link: https://github.com/sxswz213/CRSEC.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.08251v4</guid>
      <category>cs.MA</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CY</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Siyue Ren, Zhiyao Cui, Ruiqi Song, Zhen Wang, Shuyue Hu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating Named Entity Recognition: A comparative analysis of mono- and multilingual transformer models on a novel Brazilian corporate earnings call transcripts dataset</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.12212</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.12212v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Since 2018, when the Transformer architecture was introduced, Natural Language Processing has gained significant momentum with pre-trained Transformer-based models that can be fine-tuned for various tasks. Most models are pre-trained on large English corpora, making them less applicable to other languages, such as Brazilian Portuguese. In our research, we identified two models pre-trained in Brazilian Portuguese (BERTimbau and PTT5) and two multilingual models (mBERT and mT5). BERTimbau and mBERT use only the Encoder module, while PTT5 and mT5 use both the Encoder and Decoder. Our study aimed to evaluate their performance on a financial Named Entity Recognition (NER) task and determine the computational requirements for fine-tuning and inference. To this end, we developed the Brazilian Financial NER (BraFiNER) dataset, comprising sentences from Brazilian banks' earnings calls transcripts annotated using a weakly supervised approach. Additionally, we introduced a novel approach that reframes the token classification task as a text generation problem. After fine-tuning the models, we evaluated them using performance and error metrics. Our findings reveal that BERT-based models consistently outperform T5-based models. While the multilingual models exhibit comparable macro F1-scores, BERTimbau demonstrates superior performance over PTT5. In terms of error metrics, BERTimbau outperforms the other models. We also observed that PTT5 and mT5 generated sentences with changes in monetary and percentage values, highlighting the importance of accuracy and consistency in the financial domain. Our findings provide insights into the differing performance of BERT- and T5-based models for the NER task.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.12212v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1016/j.asoc.2024.112158</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Ramon Abilio, Guilherme Palermo Coelho, Ana Estela Antunes da Silva</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Frankenstein: Generating Semantic-Compositional 3D Scenes in One Tri-Plane</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.16210</link>
      <description>arXiv:2403.16210v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: We present Frankenstein, a diffusion-based framework that can generate semantic-compositional 3D scenes in a single pass. Unlike existing methods that output a single, unified 3D shape, Frankenstein simultaneously generates multiple separated shapes, each corresponding to a semantically meaningful part. The 3D scene information is encoded in one single tri-plane tensor, from which multiple Singed Distance Function (SDF) fields can be decoded to represent the compositional shapes. During training, an auto-encoder compresses tri-planes into a latent space, and then the denoising diffusion process is employed to approximate the distribution of the compositional scenes. Frankenstein demonstrates promising results in generating room interiors as well as human avatars with automatically separated parts. The generated scenes facilitate many downstream applications, such as part-wise re-texturing, object rearrangement in the room or avatar cloth re-targeting. Our project page is available at: https://wolfball.github.io/frankenstein/.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2403.16210v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.GR</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1145/3680528.3687672</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Han Yan, Yang Li, Zhennan Wu, Shenzhou Chen, Weixuan Sun, Taizhang Shang, Weizhe Liu, Tian Chen, Xiaqiang Dai, Chao Ma, Hongdong Li, Pan Ji</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Token-level Direct Preference Optimization</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.11999</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.11999v5 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Fine-tuning pre-trained Large Language Models (LLMs) is essential to align them with human values and intentions. This process often utilizes methods like pairwise comparisons and KL divergence against a reference LLM, focusing on the evaluation of full answers generated by the models. However, the generation of these responses occurs in a token level, following a sequential, auto-regressive fashion. In this paper, we introduce Token-level Direct Preference Optimization (TDPO), a novel approach to align LLMs with human preferences by optimizing policy at the token level. Unlike previous methods, which face challenges in divergence efficiency, TDPO incorporates forward KL divergence constraints for each token, improving alignment and diversity. Utilizing the Bradley-Terry model for a token-based reward system, TDPO enhances the regulation of KL divergence, while preserving simplicity without the need for explicit reward modeling. Experimental results across various text tasks demonstrate TDPO's superior performance in balancing alignment with generation diversity. Notably, fine-tuning with TDPO strikes a better balance than DPO in the controlled sentiment generation and single-turn dialogue datasets, and significantly improves the quality of generated responses compared to both DPO and PPO-based RLHF methods. Our code is open-sourced at https://github.com/Vance0124/Token-level-Direct-Preference-Optimization.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.11999v5</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yongcheng Zeng, Guoqing Liu, Weiyu Ma, Ning Yang, Haifeng Zhang, Jun Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eyes Can Deceive: Benchmarking Counterfactual Reasoning Abilities of Multi-modal Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.12966</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.12966v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Counterfactual reasoning, as a crucial manifestation of human intelligence, refers to making presuppositions based on established facts and extrapolating potential outcomes. Existing multimodal large language models (MLLMs) have exhibited impressive cognitive and reasoning capabilities, which have been examined across a wide range of Visual Question Answering (VQA) benchmarks. Nevertheless, how will existing MLLMs perform when faced with counterfactual questions? To answer this question, we first curate a novel \textbf{C}ounter\textbf{F}actual \textbf{M}ulti\textbf{M}odal reasoning benchmark, abbreviated as \textbf{CFMM}, to systematically assess the counterfactual reasoning capabilities of MLLMs. Our CFMM comprises six challenging tasks, each including hundreds of carefully human-labeled and GPT-generated counterfactual questions, to evaluate MLLM's counterfactual reasoning capabilities across diverse aspects. Through experiments, interestingly, we find that existing MLLMs prefer to believe what they see, but ignore the counterfactual presuppositions presented in the question, thereby leading to inaccurate responses. Furthermore, we evaluate a wide range of prevalent MLLMs on our proposed CFMM. The significant gap between their performance on our CFMM and that on several VQA benchmarks indicates that there is still considerable room for improvement in existing MLLMs toward approaching human-level intelligence. On the other hand, through boosting MLLMs performances on our CFMM in the future, potential avenues toward developing MLLMs with advanced intelligence can be explored.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.12966v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yian Li, Wentao Tian, Yang Jiao, Jingjing Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ECC Analyzer: Extract Trading Signal from Earnings Conference Calls using Large Language Model for Stock Performance Prediction</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.18470</link>
      <description>arXiv:2404.18470v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: In the realm of financial analytics, leveraging unstructured data, such as earnings conference calls (ECCs), to forecast stock volatility is a critical challenge that has attracted both academics and investors. While previous studies have used multimodal deep learning-based models to obtain a general view of ECCs for volatility predicting, they often fail to capture detailed, complex information. Our research introduces a novel framework: \textbf{ECC Analyzer}, which utilizes large language models (LLMs) to extract richer, more predictive content from ECCs to aid the model's prediction performance. We use the pre-trained large models to extract textual and audio features from ECCs and implement a hierarchical information extraction strategy to extract more fine-grained information. This strategy first extracts paragraph-level general information by summarizing the text and then extracts fine-grained focus sentences using Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG). These features are then fused through multimodal feature fusion to perform volatility prediction. Experimental results demonstrate that our model outperforms traditional analytical benchmarks, confirming the effectiveness of advanced LLM techniques in financial analysis.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2404.18470v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CE</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>q-fin.RM</category>
      <category>q-fin.TR</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yupeng Cao, Zhi Chen, Qingyun Pei, Nathan Jinseok Lee, K. P. Subbalakshmi, Papa Momar Ndiaye</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Markov flow policy -- deep MC</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.00877</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.00877v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Discounted algorithms often encounter evaluation errors due to their reliance on short-term estimations, which can impede their efficacy in addressing simple, short-term tasks and impose undesired temporal discounts (\(\gamma\)). Interestingly, these algorithms are often tested without applying a discount, a phenomenon we refer as the \textit{train-test bias}. In response to these challenges, we propose the Markov Flow Policy, which utilizes a non-negative neural network flow to enable comprehensive forward-view predictions. Through integration into the TD7 codebase and evaluation using the MuJoCo benchmark, we observe significant performance improvements, positioning MFP as a straightforward, practical, and easily implementable solution within the domain of average rewards algorithms.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.00877v3</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Nitsan Soffair, Gilad Katz</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hoaxpedia: A Unified Wikipedia Hoax Articles Dataset</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.02175</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.02175v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Hoaxes are a recognised form of disinformation created deliberately, with potential serious implications in the credibility of reference knowledge resources such as Wikipedia. What makes detecting Wikipedia hoaxes hard is that they often are written according to the official style guidelines. In this work, we first provide a systematic analysis of similarities and discrepancies between legitimate and hoax Wikipedia articles, and introduce Hoaxpedia, a collection of 311 hoax articles (from existing literature and official Wikipedia lists), together with semantically similar legitimate articles, which together form a binary text classification dataset aimed at fostering research in automated hoax detection. In this paper, We report results after analyzing several language models, hoax-to-legit ratios, and the amount of text classifiers are exposed to (full article vs the article's definition alone). Our results suggest that detecting deceitful content in Wikipedia based on content alone is hard but feasible, and complement our analysis with a study on the differences in distributions in edit histories, and find that looking at this feature yields better classification results than context.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.02175v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hsuvas Borkakoty, Luis Espinosa-Anke</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Machine Learning-based Approach for Solving Recurrence Relations and its use in Cost Analysis of Logic Programs</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.06972</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.06972v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Automatic static cost analysis infers information about the resources used by programs without actually running them with concrete data, and presents such information as functions of input data sizes. Most of the analysis tools for logic programs (and many for other languages), as CiaoPP, are based on setting up recurrence relations representing (bounds on) the computational cost of predicates, and solving them to find closed-form functions. Such recurrence solving is a bottleneck in current tools: many of the recurrences that arise during the analysis cannot be solved with state-of-the-art solvers, including Computer Algebra Systems (CASs), so that specific methods for different classes of recurrences need to be developed. We address such a challenge by developing a novel, general approach for solving arbitrary, constrained recurrence relations, that uses machine-learning (sparse-linear and symbolic) regression techniques to guess a candidate closed-form function, and a combination of an SMT-solver and a CAS to check if it is actually a solution of the recurrence. Our prototype implementation and its experimental evaluation within the context of the CiaoPP system show quite promising results. Overall, for the considered benchmarks, our approach outperforms state-of-the-art cost analyzers and recurrence solvers, and solves recurrences that cannot be solved by them.
  Under consideration in Theory and Practice of Logic Programming (TPLP).</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.06972v2</guid>
      <category>cs.PL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Louis Rustenholz, Maximiliano Klemen, Miguel \'Angel Carreira-Perpi\~n\'an, Pedro L\'opez-Garc\'ia</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Estimating Direct and Indirect Causal Effects of Spatiotemporal Interventions in Presence of Spatial Interference</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.08174</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.08174v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Spatial interference (SI) occurs when the treatment at one location affects the outcomes at other locations. Accounting for spatial interference in spatiotemporal settings poses further challenges as interference violates the stable unit treatment value assumption, making it infeasible for standard causal inference methods to quantify the effects of time-varying treatment at spatially varying outcomes. In this paper, we first formalize the concept of spatial interference in case of time-varying treatment assignments by extending the potential outcome framework under the assumption of no unmeasured confounding. We then propose our deep learning based potential outcome model for spatiotemporal causal inference. We utilize latent factor modeling to reduce the bias due to time-varying confounding while leveraging the power of U-Net architecture to capture global and local spatial interference in data over time. Our causal estimators are an extension of average treatment effect (ATE) for estimating direct (DATE) and indirect effects (IATE) of spatial interference on treated and untreated data. Being the first of its kind deep learning based spatiotemporal causal inference technique, our approach shows advantages over several baseline methods based on the experiment results on two synthetic datasets, with and without spatial interference. Our results on real-world climate dataset also align with domain knowledge, further demonstrating the effectiveness of our proposed method.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.08174v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sahara Ali, Omar Faruque, Jianwu Wang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning &amp; Wi-Fi: Unveiling the Path Towards AI/ML-Native IEEE 802.11 Networks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.11504</link>
      <description>arXiv:2405.11504v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Artificial intelligence (AI) and machine learning (ML) are nowadays mature technologies considered essential for driving the evolution of future communications systems. Simultaneously, Wi-Fi technology has constantly evolved over the past three decades and incorporated new features generation after generation, thus gaining in complexity. As such, researchers have observed that AI/ML functionalities may be required to address the upcoming Wi-Fi challenges that will be otherwise difficult to solve with traditional approaches. This paper discusses the role of AI/ML in current and future Wi-Fi networks and depicts the ways forward. A roadmap towards AI/ML-native Wi-Fi, key challenges, standardization efforts, and major enablers are also discussed. An exemplary use case is provided to showcase the potential of AI/ML in Wi-Fi at different adoption stages.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2405.11504v2</guid>
      <category>cs.NI</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Francesc Wilhelmi, Szymon Szott, Katarzyna Kosek-Szott, Boris Bellalta</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Weather Predictions: Super-Resolution via Deep Diffusion Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.04099</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.04099v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: This study investigates the application of deep-learning diffusion models for the super-resolution of weather data, a novel approach aimed at enhancing the spatial resolution and detail of meteorological variables. Leveraging the capabilities of diffusion models, specifically the SR3 and ResDiff architectures, we present a methodology for transforming low-resolution weather data into high-resolution outputs. Our experiments, conducted using the WeatherBench dataset, focus on the super-resolution of the two-meter temperature variable, demonstrating the models' ability to generate detailed and accurate weather maps. The results indicate that the ResDiff model, further improved by incorporating physics-based modifications, significantly outperforms traditional SR3 methods in terms of Mean Squared Error (MSE), Structural Similarity Index (SSIM), and Peak Signal-to-Noise Ratio (PSNR). This research highlights the potential of diffusion models in meteorological applications, offering insights into their effectiveness, challenges, and prospects for future advancements in weather prediction and climate analysis.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.04099v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jan Martin\r{u}, Petr \v{S}im\'anek</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DAISY: Data Adaptive Self-Supervised Early Exit for Speech Representation Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.05464</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.05464v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Self-supervised speech models have shown to be useful for various tasks, but their large size limits the use in devices with low computing power and memory. In this work, we explore early exit, an approach for reducing latency by exiting the forward process of a network early. Most approaches of early exit need a separate early exit model for each task, with some even requiring fine-tuning of the entire pretrained model. We introduce Data Adaptive Self-Supervised Early Exit (DAISY), an approach that decides when to exit based on the self-supervised loss, eliminating the need for multiple round of training and fine-tuning. DAISY matches the performance of HuBERT on the MiniSUPERB benchmark, but with much faster inference times. Our analysis on the adaptivity of DAISY shows that the model exits early (using fewer layers) on clean data while exits late (using more layers) on noisy data, dynamically adjusting the computational cost of inference based on the noise level of each sample.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.05464v2</guid>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tzu-Quan Lin, Hung-yi Lee, Hao Tang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards Effective and Efficient Non-autoregressive Decoding Using Block-based Attention Mask</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.10034</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.10034v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: This paper proposes a novel non-autoregressive (NAR) block-based Attention Mask Decoder (AMD) that flexibly balances performance-efficiency trade-offs for Conformer ASR systems. AMD performs parallel NAR inference within contiguous blocks of output labels that are concealed using attention masks, while conducting left-to-right AR prediction and history context amalgamation between blocks. A beam search algorithm is designed to leverage a dynamic fusion of CTC, AR Decoder, and AMD probabilities. Experiments on the LibriSpeech-100hr corpus suggest the tripartite Decoder incorporating the AMD module produces a maximum decoding speed-up ratio of 1.73x over the baseline CTC+AR decoding, while incurring no statistically significant word error rate (WER) increase on the test sets. When operating with the same decoding real time factors, statistically significant WER reductions of up to 0.7% and 0.3% absolute (5.3% and 6.1% relative) were obtained over the CTC+AR baseline.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.10034v3</guid>
      <category>cs.SD</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>eess.AS</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Tianzi Wang, Xurong Xie, Zhaoqing Li, Shoukang Hu, Zengrui Jin, Jiajun Deng, Mingyu Cui, Shujie Hu, Mengzhe Geng, Guinan Li, Helen Meng, Xunying Liu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are Small Language Models Ready to Compete with Large Language Models for Practical Applications?</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.11402</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.11402v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: The rapid rise of Language Models (LMs) has expanded their use in several applications. Yet, due to constraints of model size, associated cost, or proprietary restrictions, utilizing state-of-the-art (SOTA) LLMs is not always feasible. With open, smaller LMs emerging, more applications can leverage their capabilities, but selecting the right LM can be challenging as smaller LMs don't perform well universally. This work tries to bridge this gap by proposing a framework to experimentally evaluate small, open LMs in practical settings through measuring semantic correctness of outputs across three practical aspects: task types, application domains and reasoning types, using diverse prompt styles. It also conducts an in-depth comparison of 10 small, open LMs to identify best LM and prompt style depending on specific application requirement using the proposed framework. We also show that if selected appropriately, they can outperform SOTA LLMs like DeepSeek-v2, GPT-4o-mini, Gemini-1.5-Pro, and even compete with GPT-4o.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.11402v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Neelabh Sinha, Vinija Jain, Aman Chadha</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards Learning Abductive Reasoning using VSA Distributed Representations</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2406.19121</link>
      <description>arXiv:2406.19121v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: We introduce the Abductive Rule Learner with Context-awareness (ARLC), a model that solves abstract reasoning tasks based on Learn-VRF. ARLC features a novel and more broadly applicable training objective for abductive reasoning, resulting in better interpretability and higher accuracy when solving Raven's progressive matrices (RPM). ARLC allows both programming domain knowledge and learning the rules underlying a data distribution. We evaluate ARLC on the I-RAVEN dataset, showcasing state-of-the-art accuracy across both in-distribution and out-of-distribution (unseen attribute-rule pairs) tests. ARLC surpasses neuro-symbolic and connectionist baselines, including large language models, despite having orders of magnitude fewer parameters. We show ARLC's robustness to post-programming training by incrementally learning from examples on top of programmed knowledge, which only improves its performance and does not result in catastrophic forgetting of the programmed solution. We validate ARLC's seamless transfer learning from a 2x2 RPM constellation to unseen constellations. Our code is available at https://github.com/IBM/abductive-rule-learner-with-context-awareness.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2406.19121v3</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.SC</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Giacomo Camposampiero, Michael Hersche, Aleksandar Terzi\'c, Roger Wattenhofer, Abu Sebastian, Abbas Rahimi</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CaFNet: A Confidence-Driven Framework for Radar Camera Depth Estimation</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.00697</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.00697v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Depth estimation is critical in autonomous driving for interpreting 3D scenes accurately. Recently, radar-camera depth estimation has become of sufficient interest due to the robustness and low-cost properties of radar. Thus, this paper introduces a two-stage, end-to-end trainable Confidence-aware Fusion Net (CaFNet) for dense depth estimation, combining RGB imagery with sparse and noisy radar point cloud data. The first stage addresses radar-specific challenges, such as ambiguous elevation and noisy measurements, by predicting a radar confidence map and a preliminary coarse depth map. A novel approach is presented for generating the ground truth for the confidence map, which involves associating each radar point with its corresponding object to identify potential projection surfaces. These maps, together with the initial radar input, are processed by a second encoder. For the final depth estimation, we innovate a confidence-aware gated fusion mechanism to integrate radar and image features effectively, thereby enhancing the reliability of the depth map by filtering out radar noise. Our methodology, evaluated on the nuScenes dataset, demonstrates superior performance, improving upon the current leading model by 3.2% in Mean Absolute Error (MAE) and 2.7% in Root Mean Square Error (RMSE). Code: https://github.com/harborsarah/CaFNet</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.00697v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>eess.SP</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Huawei Sun, Hao Feng, Julius Ott, Lorenzo Servadei, Robert Wille</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ConCodeEval: Evaluating Large Language Models for Code Constraints in Domain-Specific Languages</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.03387</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.03387v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Recent work shows Large Language Models (LLMs) struggle to understand natural language constraints for various text generation tasks in zero- and few-shot settings. While, in the code domain, there is wide usage of constraints in code format to maintain the integrity of code written in Domain-Specific Languages (DSLs) like JSON and YAML which are widely used for system-level programming tasks in enterprises. Given that LLMs are increasingly used for system-level code tasks, evaluating if they can comprehend these code constraints is crucial. However, no work has been done to evaluate their controllability over code constraints. Hence, we introduce ConCodeEval, a first-of-its-kind benchmark having two novel tasks for code constraints across five representations. Our findings suggest that language models struggle with code constraints. Code languages that perform excellently for normal code tasks do not perform well when the same languages represent fine-grained constraints.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.03387v2</guid>
      <category>cs.SE</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Mehant Kammakomati, Sameer Pimparkhede, Srikanth Tamilselvam, Prince Kumar, Pushpak Bhattacharyya</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jailbreak Attacks and Defenses Against Large Language Models: A Survey</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.04295</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.04295v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) have performed exceptionally in various text-generative tasks, including question answering, translation, code completion, etc. However, the over-assistance of LLMs has raised the challenge of "jailbreaking", which induces the model to generate malicious responses against the usage policy and society by designing adversarial prompts. With the emergence of jailbreak attack methods exploiting different vulnerabilities in LLMs, the corresponding safety alignment measures are also evolving. In this paper, we propose a comprehensive and detailed taxonomy of jailbreak attack and defense methods. For instance, the attack methods are divided into black-box and white-box attacks based on the transparency of the target model. Meanwhile, we classify defense methods into prompt-level and model-level defenses. Additionally, we further subdivide these attack and defense methods into distinct sub-classes and present a coherent diagram illustrating their relationships. We also conduct an investigation into the current evaluation methods and compare them from different perspectives. Our findings aim to inspire future research and practical implementations in safeguarding LLMs against adversarial attacks. Above all, although jailbreak remains a significant concern within the community, we believe that our work enhances the understanding of this domain and provides a foundation for developing more secure LLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.04295v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CR</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Sibo Yi, Yule Liu, Zhen Sun, Tianshuo Cong, Xinlei He, Jiaxing Song, Ke Xu, Qi Li</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Etalon: Holistic Performance Evaluation Framework for LLM Inference Systems</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.07000</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.07000v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Serving large language models (LLMs) in production can incur substantial costs, which has prompted recent advances in inference system optimizations. Today, these systems are evaluated against conventional latency and throughput metrics (eg. TTFT, TBT, Normalised Latency and TPOT). However, these metrics fail to fully capture the nuances of LLM inference, leading to an incomplete assessment of user-facing performance crucial for real-time applications such as chat and translation. In this paper, we first identify the pitfalls of current performance metrics in evaluating LLM inference systems. We then propose Etalon, a comprehensive performance evaluation framework that includes fluidity-index -- a novel metric designed to reflect the intricacies of the LLM inference process and its impact on real-time user experience. Finally, we evaluate various existing open-source platforms and model-as-a-service offerings using Etalon, discussing their strengths and weaknesses. Etalon is available at https://github.com/project-etalon/etalon.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.07000v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.DC</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Amey Agrawal, Anmol Agarwal, Nitin Kedia, Jayashree Mohan, Souvik Kundu, Nipun Kwatra, Ramachandran Ramjee, Alexey Tumanov</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Early Explorations of Lightweight Models for Wound Segmentation on Mobile Devices</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2407.07605</link>
      <description>arXiv:2407.07605v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: The aging population poses numerous challenges to healthcare, including the increase in chronic wounds in the elderly. The current approach to wound assessment by therapists based on photographic documentation is subjective, highlighting the need for computer-aided wound recognition from smartphone photos. This offers objective and convenient therapy monitoring, while being accessible to patients from their home at any time. However, despite research in mobile image segmentation, there is a lack of focus on mobile wound segmentation. To address this gap, we conduct initial research on three lightweight architectures to investigate their suitability for smartphone-based wound segmentation. Using public datasets and UNet as a baseline, our results are promising, with both ENet and TopFormer, as well as the larger UNeXt variant, showing comparable performance to UNet. Furthermore, we deploy the models into a smartphone app for visual assessment of live segmentation, where results demonstrate the effectiveness of TopFormer in distinguishing wounds from wound-coloured objects. While our study highlights the potential of transformer models for mobile wound segmentation, future work should aim to further improve the mask contours.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2407.07605v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1007/978-3-031-70893-0_21</arxiv:DOI>
      <dc:creator>Vanessa Borst, Timo Dittus, Konstantin M\"uller, Samuel Kounev</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TaSL: Task Skill Localization and Consolidation for Language Model Continual Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.05200</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.05200v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Language model continual learning (CL) has recently attracted significant interest for its ability to adapt large language models (LLMs) to dynamic real-world scenarios without retraining. A major challenge in this domain is catastrophic forgetting, where models lose previously acquired knowledge upon learning new tasks. Existing approaches commonly utilize multiple parameter-efficient fine-tuning (PEFT) blocks to acquire task-specific knowledge, yet these methods are inefficient and fail to leverage potential knowledge transfer across tasks. In this paper, we introduce a novel CL framework for language models, named Task Skill Localization and Consolidation (TaSL), which boosts knowledge transfer without depending on memory replay. TaSL initially segregates the model into 'skill units' based on parameter dependencies, allowing for more precise control. Subsequently, it employs a novel group-wise skill localization technique to ascertain the importance distribution of skill units for a new task. By comparing this importance distribution with those from previous tasks, we implement a fine-grained skill consolidation strategy that retains task-specific knowledge, thereby preventing forgetting, and updates task-shared knowledge, which facilitates bi-directional knowledge transfer. As a result, TaSL achieves an optimal balance between retaining prior knowledge and excelling in new tasks. TaSL also demonstrates strong generalizability, making it suitable for various base models and adaptable to PEFT methods like LoRA. Furthermore, it offers notable extensibility, supporting enhancements through integration with memory replay techniques. Comprehensive experiments conducted on two CL benchmarks, involving models ranging from 220M to 7B parameters, affirm the effectiveness of TaSL and its variants across different settings.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.05200v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Yujie Feng, Xu Chu, Yongxin Xu, Zexin Lu, Bo Liu, Philip S. Yu, Xiao-Ming Wu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anchored Preference Optimization and Contrastive Revisions: Addressing Underspecification in Alignment</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.06266</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.06266v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) are often aligned using contrastive alignment objectives and preference pair datasets. The interaction between model, paired data, and objective makes alignment a complicated procedure, sometimes producing subpar results. We study this and find that (i) preference data gives a better learning signal when the underlying responses are contrastive, and (ii) alignment objectives lead to better performance when they specify more control over the model during training. Based on these insights, we introduce Contrastive Learning from AI Revisions (CLAIR), a data-creation method which leads to more contrastive preference pairs, and Anchored Preference Optimization (APO), a controllable and more stable alignment objective. We align Llama-3-8B-Instruct using various comparable datasets and alignment objectives and measure MixEval-Hard scores, which correlate highly with human judgments. The CLAIR preferences lead to the strongest performance out of all datasets, and APO consistently outperforms less controllable objectives. Our best model, trained on 32K CLAIR preferences with APO, improves Llama-3-8B-Instruct by 7.65%, closing the gap with GPT4-turbo by 45%. Our code is available at https://github.com/ContextualAI/CLAIR_and_APO.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.06266v3</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Karel D'Oosterlinck, Winnie Xu, Chris Develder, Thomas Demeester, Amanpreet Singh, Christopher Potts, Douwe Kiela, Shikib Mehri</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prompt-Agnostic Adversarial Perturbation for Customized Diffusion Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.10571</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.10571v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Diffusion models have revolutionized customized text-to-image generation, allowing for efficient synthesis of photos from personal data with textual descriptions. However, these advancements bring forth risks including privacy breaches and unauthorized replication of artworks. Previous researches primarily center around using prompt-specific methods to generate adversarial examples to protect personal images, yet the effectiveness of existing methods is hindered by constrained adaptability to different prompts. In this paper, we introduce a Prompt-Agnostic Adversarial Perturbation (PAP) method for customized diffusion models. PAP first models the prompt distribution using a Laplace Approximation, and then produces prompt-agnostic perturbations by maximizing a disturbance expectation based on the modeled distribution. This approach effectively tackles the prompt-agnostic attacks, leading to improved defense stability. Extensive experiments in face privacy and artistic style protection, demonstrate the superior generalization of our method in comparison to existing techniques.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.10571v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Cong Wan, Yuhang He, Xiang Song, Yihong Gong</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Causal-Guided Active Learning for Debiasing Large Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.12942</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.12942v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Although achieving promising performance, recent analyses show that current generative large language models (LLMs) may still capture dataset biases and utilize them for generation, leading to poor generalizability and harmfulness of LLMs. However, due to the diversity of dataset biases and the over-optimization problem, previous prior-knowledge-based debiasing methods and fine-tuning-based debiasing methods may not be suitable for current LLMs. To address this issue, we explore combining active learning with the causal mechanisms and propose a casual-guided active learning (CAL) framework, which utilizes LLMs itself to automatically and autonomously identify informative biased samples and induce the bias patterns. Then a cost-effective and efficient in-context learning based method is employed to prevent LLMs from utilizing dataset biases during generation. Experimental results show that CAL can effectively recognize typical biased instances and induce various bias patterns for debiasing LLMs.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.12942v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Li Du, Zhouhao Sun, Xiao Ding, Yixuan Ma, Yang Zhao, Kaitao Qiu, Ting Liu, Bing Qin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Temporal Ensemble Logic</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.14443</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.14443v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: We introduce Temporal Ensemble Logic (TEL), a monadic, first-order modal logic for linear-time temporal reasoning. TEL includes primitive temporal constructs such as ``always up to $t$ time later'' ($\Box_t$), ``sometimes before $t$ time in the future'' ($\Diamond_t$), and ``$t$-time later'' $\varphi_t$. TEL has been motivated from the requirement for rigor and reproducibility for cohort specification and discovery in clinical and population health research, to fill a gap in formalizing temporal reasoning in biomedicine. Existing logical frameworks such as linear temporal logic are too restrictive to express temporal and sequential properties in biomedicine, or too permissive in semantic constructs, such as in Halpern-Shoham logic, to serve this purpose. In this paper, we first introduce TEL in a general set up, with discrete and dense time as special cases. We then focus on the theoretical development of discrete TEL on the temporal domain of positive integers $\mathbb{N}^+$, denoted as ${\rm TEL}_{\mathbb{N}^+}$. ${\rm TEL}_{\mathbb{N}^+}$ is strictly more expressive than the standard monadic second order logic, characterized by B\"{u}chi automata. We present its formal semantics, a proof system, and provide a proof for the undecidability of the satisfiability of ${\rm TEL}_{\mathbb{N}^+}$. We also include initial results on expressiveness and decidability fragments for ${\rm TEL}_{\mathbb{N}^+}$, followed by application outlook and discussions.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.14443v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LO</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.FL</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Guo-Qiang Zhang</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards Graph Prompt Learning: A Survey and Beyond</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.14520</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.14520v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Large-scale "pre-train and prompt learning" paradigms have demonstrated remarkable adaptability, enabling broad applications across diverse domains such as question answering, image recognition, and multimodal retrieval. This approach fully leverages the potential of large-scale pre-trained models, reducing downstream data requirements and computational costs while enhancing model applicability across various tasks. Graphs, as versatile data structures that capture relationships between entities, play pivotal roles in fields such as social network analysis, recommender systems, and biological graphs. Despite the success of pre-train and prompt learning paradigms in Natural Language Processing (NLP) and Computer Vision (CV), their application in graph domains remains nascent. In graph-structured data, not only do the node and edge features often have disparate distributions, but the topological structures also differ significantly. This diversity in graph data can lead to incompatible patterns or gaps between pre-training and fine-tuning on downstream graphs. We aim to bridge this gap by summarizing methods for alleviating these disparities. This includes exploring prompt design methodologies, comparing related techniques, assessing application scenarios and datasets, and identifying unresolved problems and challenges. This survey categorizes over 100 relevant works in this field, summarizing general design principles and the latest applications, including text-attributed graphs, molecules, proteins, and recommendation systems. Through this extensive review, we provide a foundational understanding of graph prompt learning, aiming to impact not only the graph mining community but also the broader Artificial General Intelligence (AGI) community.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.14520v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.SI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Qingqing Long, Yuchen Yan, Peiyan Zhang, Chen Fang, Wentao Cui, Zhiyuan Ning, Meng Xiao, Ning Cao, Xiao Luo, Lingjun Xu, Shiyue Jiang, Zheng Fang, Chong Chen, Xian-Sheng Hua, Yuanchun Zhou</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A global AI community requires language-diverse publishing</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.14772</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.14772v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: In this provocation, we discuss the English dominance of the AI research community, arguing that the requirement for English language publishing upholds and reinforces broader regimes of extraction in AI. While large language models and machine translation have been celebrated as a way to break down barriers, we regard their use as a symptom of linguistic exclusion of scientists and potential readers. We propose alternative futures for a healthier publishing culture, organized around three themes: administering conferences in the languages of the country in which they are held, instructing peer reviewers not to adjudicate the language appropriateness of papers, and offering opportunities to publish and present in multiple languages. We welcome new translations of this piece. Please contact the authors if you would like to contribute one.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.14772v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CL</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Haley Lepp, Parth Sarin</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Permuted Autoregressive Approach to Word-Level Recognition for Urdu Digital Text</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.15119</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.15119v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: This research paper introduces a novel word-level Optical Character Recognition (OCR) model specifically designed for digital Urdu text, leveraging transformer-based architectures and attention mechanisms to address the distinct challenges of Urdu script recognition, including its diverse text styles, fonts, and variations. The model employs a permuted autoregressive sequence (PARSeq) architecture, which enhances its performance by enabling context-aware inference and iterative refinement through the training of multiple token permutations. This method allows the model to adeptly manage character reordering and overlapping characters, commonly encountered in Urdu script. Trained on a dataset comprising approximately 160,000 Urdu text images, the model demonstrates a high level of accuracy in capturing the intricacies of Urdu script, achieving a CER of 0.178. Despite ongoing challenges in handling certain text variations, the model exhibits superior accuracy and effectiveness in practical applications. Future work will focus on refining the model through advanced data augmentation techniques and the integration of context-aware language models to further enhance its performance and robustness in Urdu text recognition.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.15119v3</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Ahmed Mustafa, Muhammad Tahir Rafique, Muhammad Ijlal Baig, Hasan Sajid, Muhammad Jawad Khan, Karam Dad Kallu</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anomaly Detection in Time Series of EDFA Pump Currents to Monitor Degeneration Processes using Fuzzy Clustering</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.15268</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.15268v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: This article proposes a novel fuzzy clustering based anomaly detection method for pump current time series of EDFA systems. The proposed change detection framework (CDF) strategically combines the advantages of entropy analysis (EA) and principle component analysis (PCA) with fuzzy clustering procedures. In the framework, EA is applied for dynamic selection of features for reduction of the feature space and increase of computational performance. Furthermore, PCA is utilized to extract features from the raw feature space to enable generalization capability of the subsequent fuzzy clustering procedures. Three different fuzzy clustering methods, more precisely the fuzzy clustering algorithm, a probabilistic clustering algorithm and a possibilistic clustering algorithm are evaluated for performance and generalization. Hence, the proposed framework has the innovative feature to detect changes in pump current time series at an early stage for arbitrary points of operation, compared to state-of-the-art predefined alarms in commercially used EDFAs. Moreover, the approach is implemented and tested using experimental data. In addition, the proposed framework enables further approaches of applying decentralized predictive maintenance for optical fiber networks.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.15268v2</guid>
      <category>eess.SP</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <arxiv:DOI>10.1109/ICMLCN59089.2024.10624870</arxiv:DOI>
      <arxiv:journal_reference>2024 IEEE International Conference on Machine Learning for Communication and Networking (ICMLCN)</arxiv:journal_reference>
      <dc:creator>Dominic Schneider, Lutz Rapp, Christoph Ament</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Robust Statistical Scaling of Outlier Scores: Improving the Quality of Outlier Probabilities for Outliers (Extended Version)</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.15874</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.15874v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Outlier detection algorithms typically assign an outlier score to each observation in a dataset, indicating the degree to which an observation is an outlier. However, these scores are often not comparable across algorithms and can be difficult for humans to interpret. Statistical scaling addresses this problem by transforming outlier scores into outlier probabilities without using ground-truth labels, thereby improving interpretability and comparability across algorithms. However, the quality of this transformation can be different for outliers and inliers. Missing outliers in scenarios where they are of particular interest - such as healthcare, finance, or engineering - can be costly or dangerous. Thus, ensuring good probabilities for outliers is essential. This paper argues that statistical scaling, as commonly used in the literature, does not produce equally good probabilities for outliers as for inliers. Therefore, we propose robust statistical scaling, which uses robust estimators to improve the probabilities for outliers. We evaluate several variants of our method against other outlier score transformations for real-world datasets and outlier detection algorithms, where it can improve the probabilities for outliers.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.15874v2</guid>
      <category>cs.LG</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Philipp R\"ochner, Henrique O. Marques, Ricardo J. G. B. Campello, Arthur Zimek, Franz Rothlauf</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Novel Methods for Analyzing Cellular Interactions in Deep Learning-Based Image Cytometry: Spatial Interaction Potential and Co-Localization Index</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.16008</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.16008v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: The study presents a novel approach for quantifying cellular interactions in digital pathology using deep learning-based image cytometry. Traditional methods struggle with the diversity and heterogeneity of cells within tissues. To address this, we introduce the Spatial Interaction Potential (SIP) and the Co-Localization Index (CLI), leveraging deep learning classification probabilities. SIP assesses the potential for cell-to-cell interactions, similar to an electric field, while CLI incorporates distances between cells, accounting for dynamic cell movements. Our approach enhances traditional methods, providing a more sophisticated analysis of cellular interactions. We validate SIP and CLI through simulations and apply them to colorectal cancer specimens, demonstrating strong correlations with actual biological data. This innovative method offers significant improvements in understanding cellular interactions and has potential applications in various fields of digital pathology.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.16008v2</guid>
      <category>q-bio.QM</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Toru Nagasaka, Kimihiro Yamashita, Mitsugu Fujita</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Identification of Prognostic Biomarkers for Stage III Non-Small Cell Lung Carcinoma in Female Nonsmokers Using Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.16068</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.16068v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Lung cancer remains a leading cause of cancer-related deaths globally, with non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC) being the most common subtype. This study aimed to identify key biomarkers associated with stage III NSCLC in non-smoking females using gene expression profiling from the GDS3837 dataset. Utilizing XGBoost, a machine learning algorithm, the analysis achieved a strong predictive performance with an AUC score of 0.835. The top biomarkers identified - CCAAT enhancer binding protein alpha (C/EBP-alpha), lactate dehydrogenase A4 (LDHA), UNC-45 myosin chaperone B (UNC-45B), checkpoint kinase 1 (CHK1), and hypoxia-inducible factor 1 subunit alpha (HIF-1-alpha) - have been validated in the literature as being significantly linked to lung cancer. These findings highlight the potential of these biomarkers for early diagnosis and personalized therapy, emphasizing the value of integrating machine learning with molecular profiling in cancer research.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.16068v2</guid>
      <category>q-bio.GN</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <category>stat.ML</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Huili Zheng, Qimin Zhang, Yiru Gong, Zheyan Liu, Shaohan Chen</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LLaVA-SG: Leveraging Scene Graphs as Visual Semantic Expression in Vision-Language Models</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.16224</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.16224v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Recent advances in large vision-language models (VLMs) typically employ vision encoders based on the Vision Transformer (ViT) architecture. The division of the images into patches by ViT results in a fragmented perception, thereby hindering the visual understanding capabilities of VLMs. In this paper, we propose an innovative enhancement to address this limitation by introducing a Scene Graph Expression (SGE) module in VLMs. This module extracts and structurally expresses the complex semantic information within images, thereby improving the foundational perception and understanding abilities of VLMs. Extensive experiments demonstrate that integrating our SGE module significantly enhances the VLM's performance in vision-language tasks, indicating its effectiveness in preserving intricate semantic details and facilitating better visual understanding.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.16224v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Jingyi Wang, Jianzhong Ju, Jian Luan, Zhidong Deng</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dissecting Out-of-Distribution Detection and Open-Set Recognition: A Critical Analysis of Methods and Benchmarks</title>
      <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2408.16757</link>
      <description>arXiv:2408.16757v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Detecting test-time distribution shift has emerged as a key capability for safely deployed machine learning models, with the question being tackled under various guises in recent years. In this paper, we aim to provide a consolidated view of the two largest sub-fields within the community: out-of-distribution (OOD) detection and open-set recognition (OSR). In particular, we aim to provide rigorous empirical analysis of different methods across settings and provide actionable takeaways for practitioners and researchers. Concretely, we make the following contributions: (i) We perform rigorous cross-evaluation between state-of-the-art methods in the OOD detection and OSR settings and identify a strong correlation between the performances of methods for them; (ii) We propose a new, large-scale benchmark setting which we suggest better disentangles the problem tackled by OOD detection and OSR, re-evaluating state-of-the-art OOD detection and OSR methods in this setting; (iii) We surprisingly find that the best performing method on standard benchmarks (Outlier Exposure) struggles when tested at scale, while scoring rules which are sensitive to the deep feature magnitude consistently show promise; and (iv) We conduct empirical analysis to explain these phenomena and highlight directions for future research. Code: https://github.com/Visual-AI/Dissect-OOD-OSR</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">oai:arXiv.org:2408.16757v2</guid>
      <category>cs.CV</category>
      <category>cs.AI</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <arxiv:announce_type>replace-cross</arxiv:announce_type>
      <dc:rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</dc:rights>
      <dc:creator>Hongjun Wang, Sagar Vaze, Kai Han</dc:creator>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>